<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>The ‘Nine Days’ <footnote>
            <para>Based on the Kitzur Shulchon Oruch, Chapters 122-125 and Rabbi Eider’s “Summary of Halachos of the Three Weeks”</para>
        </footnote>
    </title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May engagements take place during the Nine Days? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is it permissible to cut nails during the Nine Days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Mishenichnas Av memaatin besimcha.” Does this include Rosh Chodesh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one has a lawsuit in court, what should he try to do? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May painting, building or decorating be done? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why can’t we eat meat or drink wine in the Nine Days? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May some people eat meat? Is chicken different in this halacha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is a siyum? When is it made? Who can participate? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it prohibited to launder clothes? Is wearing freshly laundered clothes permitted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one has no dean clothes, may he do some laundering?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a difference between various kinds of garments concerning the prohibition of wearing freshly washed clothes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one ‘prepare’ clean clothes for the ‘Nine Days’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are linen, towels, or tablecloths included in the <glossterm>issur</glossterm> (prohibition)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which of the above prohibitions are lifted for Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one purchase new sneakers for Tisha B’Av? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Needlework and embroidery are prohibited. How about repairing and patching?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Usual washing and bathing for pleasure is prohibited even in cold water. In which cases would a man be permitted to wash?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When washing is permissible, can soap and shampoo be used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one wash one’s face, hands, or feet with cold or warm water?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From the seventh day of Av, restrictions are more serious. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is Havdala made on Motzei Shabbos (parshas Matos/Masei)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Shabbos prior to Tisha B’Av has a special name. What? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is singing permissible during the Nine Nays?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
