<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="beshalach" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Beshalach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the Jews taken out through a <emphasis role="bold">distant</emphasis> route after leaving Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Yoseif’s ‘ark’ (his remains) was taken out by <emphasis role="bold">Moshe</emphasis>. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the Jews get weapons in the desert? How many Jews remained in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Yoseif tell his own children to carry him to Eretz Yisroel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of the commandment, “Let them return and rest. . . in front of Baal Tzfon”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is Hashem’s honor increased? What compliment is given to the Jews here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Paroh find out that the Jews left for good?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we say the <glossterm>shira</glossterm> (song) ‘Az Yashir’ on <glossterm>Shvi’i shel Pesach</glossterm> (the seventh day of Pesach)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Paroh convince his people to join him in pursuing the Jews?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the basis for the statement, “The best <glossterm>Mitzri</glossterm> (Egyptian) should be killed”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint that the Jewish nation was following the Ramah (Reb Moshe Isserles) in <glossterm>halacha</glossterm> (Jewish law)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It is said that the Rashbi, the Ari, and the Baal Shem Tov’s teachings will bring Moshiach. Where is this hinted in the parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the Jews say to Moshe when they noticed the Egyptians coming toward them? What did Moshe answer them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the real Jewish way to respond in the face of trouble? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which merits caused the splitting of the sea before the Jews?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of judgment was held over the Jews at that time? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the <glossterm>mashal</glossterm> (example) of a father and his son explain what happened near <glossterm>Yam Suf</glossterm> (the Red
                Sea)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How were the Jews assured that the Egyptians were not coming out on the other side (of the sea)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint about <glossterm>techiyas hameisim</glossterm> (resurrection of the dead) in the shira?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what ways were the Jews at the Red Sea superior to the <glossterm>Nevi’im</glossterm> (Prophets)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were three kinds of Egyptian people and they were punished differently at the sea. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The word <glossterm>yemincha</glossterm> is mentioned several times in the shira. What is said about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Miriam called <glossterm>Neviah</glossterm> (Prophetess)? And why ‘sister of Aharon’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe have to force the people to ‘move on’ after <glossterm>krias Yam Suf</glossterm> (the parting of the Red Sea)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvos were given in Marah? And which tests?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the diseases of the Egyptians were not to be put upon us, why does it say that Hashem will <emphasis role="bold">heal</emphasis> us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection are the numbers 12 and 70 mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long did their food leftovers (from Mitzrayim) last? When did the <glossterm>mon</glossterm> (manna) come?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"><glossterm>Bnei Yisroel</glossterm> (the Children of Israel) asked for bread and meat. How was it given to them? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what ways did the mon test Bnei Yisroel? What happened on Shabbos? Which halacha comes from it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to our Sages, getting a <glossterm>shidduch</glossterm> (marriage partner) and getting
                    <glossterm>parnasah</glossterm> (livelihood) are likened to krias Yam Suf. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which places in the davening is krias Yam Suf mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The mon was described as lying in a box. Explain why.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What scientific experiment does Rashi suggest in connection with mon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What ‘big miracle’ happened concerning the amount of the mon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the nations of the world find out about the taste of mon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did the mon come down on Yom Tov? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Moshe told to put away a jar of man for remembrance?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When did the mon stop? How many years did it come?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the story of Amalek written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Chur? Kalev? Why is Chur mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe do at the time of battle to confuse Amalek?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Yehoshua told to do to Amalek in the future?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
