<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="bo" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Bo</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Come to Paroh,” etc. For what purpose?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If Hashem hardened Paroh’s heart, why does Paroh deserve punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of the makos if Paroh would refuse anyway?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the <glossterm>arbeh</glossterm> (locusts) supposed to do to the land of Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint in the first posuk that three makos will come? (See Baal Haturim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Paroh’s servants say to him when they heard about the locusts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Paroh want to compromise upon hearing about the locusts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What <emphasis role="bold">historic</emphasis> description is given to arbeh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A similar description is given to another locust attack. Which was greater?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to the Midrash, how did Moshe’s prayers help to change the astrologers’ prediction?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the removal of the locusts different from the removal of the frogs?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the difference between the first and last three days of darkness?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was Paroh willing to compromise after being hit with darkness? What was Moshe’s answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What two important purposes were served by the makah of darkness?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What warning did Paroh give to Moshe after the darkness? What did Moshe answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Hashem <emphasis role="bold">insist</emphasis> that Moshe ask the people to get the ‘good things’ from the Egyptians?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When was Moshe told about the last makah (<glossterm>makas bechoros</glossterm>, slaying of the firstborn)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe say ‘around midnight’ while Hashem said ‘at midnight’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the tenth plague of the firstborn affect the captives? The slaves? The cattle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that despite everything, Paroh <emphasis role="bold">was</emphasis> accorded his respects by Moshe.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where did Hashem speak to Moshe about the <glossterm>Korban Pesach</glossterm> (Passover sacrifice)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Moshe told about Rosh Chodesh? About the month of Nissan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which part of the day did Hashem speak to Moshe? What difficulty did Moshe have?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were they told only this one time to take the lamb four days before its sacrifice?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is the Korban Pesach brought? Who may eat from it? Who may not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the korban called <glossterm>Pesach</glossterm>? On which side of the door was the blood put? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which days of Pesach is the eating of <glossterm>matzo</glossterm> (unleavened bread) <emphasis role="bold">voluntary</emphasis>? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for eating <glossterm>chametz</glossterm> (leaven)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What may be done on Yom Tov which may not be done on Shabbos? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Of the ‘four sons,’ whose questions and answers are mentioned in our parsha? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The Jews dwelt... 430 years!” But they were in Mitzrayim only 210 years? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which other mitzvos (connected with <glossterm>yetzias Mitzmyim</glossterm>, the exodus from Egypt) are mentioned in the two
                <glossterm>parshiyos</glossterm> of tefillin (<glossterm>Kadaish</glossterm>, <glossterm>Vehaya</glossterm>) at the end of this <glossterm>sedra</glossterm> (parsha)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
