<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="ki-sissa" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Ki Sissa</title>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why weren’t the Jews counted directly? Were they ever counted directly?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What halacha about counting people do we learn from the second posuk?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How was Moshe shown the half-Shekel? What else was he shown in this way?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How many <glossterm>zuzim</glossterm> in a Shekel? How many <glossterm>geira</glossterm> in a zuz?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is the word <glossterm>terumah</glossterm> mentioned three times?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did they spend the silver from the two counts?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why was the count exactly the same both times? Was there a miracle in it?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What was the <glossterm>kiyor</glossterm>? Who used it? For what?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Which halacha is derived from the parsha of kiyor?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did the oil contain besides the olive oil?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What was this oil used for? What are the opinions of Rabbi Yehuda and Rabbi Meir on the preparation of this oil?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What was the weight of the aromatic herbs? The measure of the oil?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“Anything touching <emphasis role="bold">them</emphasis> should become <emphasis role="bold">holy</emphasis>.” Touching whom? Holy for
                what?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Our Sages said that all of the oil remained intact. How do we know?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What are the two prohibitions about the oil? Punishment for transgressing?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How many herbs were used for the <glossterm>ketores</glossterm> (incense)? How many are mentioned?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">One of the herbs didn’t have a good aroma. Which? What do we learn from this fact?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Into how many portions was it divided? Why? What about the extras?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How does Rashi explain <glossterm>chochma</glossterm>, <glossterm>tevuna</glossterm>, <glossterm>daas</glossterm>? Is this similar to the
                explanation given in Tanya for <glossterm>chochma</glossterm>, <glossterm>binah</glossterm>, <glossterm>daas</glossterm>? How?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is the subject of Shabbos mentioned here?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Shabbos is a sign between Hashem and the Jews. How?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">For whom is this sign intended? Purpose?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What are the punishments for desecrating the Shabbos? <glossterm>Beshogeig</glossterm>, <glossterm>bemeizid</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>behasraah</glossterm>?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is Shabbos called <glossterm>Shabbos Shabbaton</glossterm>? What else is called by this title?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Torah is not necessarily arranged in chronological order.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What wording is used in the Hebrew version of the above rule?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is the Torah likened to a <glossterm>kallah</glossterm>? (Two reasons.)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How was it possible for Moshe to learn the whole Torah in such a short time?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did the people mistakenly decide that Moshe was late in his return?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Which two things did the <glossterm>Satan</glossterm> do to confuse the people?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Prove that they only asked for a leader to substitute for Moshe, not for a deity.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon decide to ask for the <emphasis role="bold">women’s</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">children’s</emphasis> jewelry?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Who actually donated the jewelry? Proof?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">After Aharon threw the gold into the fire, <emphasis role="bold">who</emphasis> produced the <glossterm>egel hazahav</glossterm> (golden calf)?
                (Two opinions.)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Prove that the mixed multitude of <glossterm>erev rav</glossterm> (Egyptian converts) started the whole thing.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon feel forced to announce a celebration for them? Why for the <emphasis role="bold">next</emphasis> day?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t he ask them to build the altar instead of building it himself?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What happened to Chur? Why? How was he related to Aharon?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why was it so easy for them to get up early the next morning? Did they awaken so quickly for Matan Torah? What can we learn from it?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What kind of mussar did Moshe get from the Heavenly Court?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why does it say “<emphasis role="bold">Your</emphasis> nation sinned” rather than “<emphasis role="bold">the</emphasis> nation”?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why were the Jews called a stiff-necked people?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe get the hint that prayer might still help?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What reason did Moshe give to Hashem not to be angry at them?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did he mention here the three Patriarchs?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did Hashem respond to Moshe’s prayers?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">On which days do we read Moshe’s prayer in the Torah? Why?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“They (the tablets) are the doings of Hashem.” Give two interpretations for this.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When Yehoshua said, “Hear a sound of war in the camp,” what did Moshe answer?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What reason did Moshe have (from a halacha) to break the <glossterm>Luchos</glossterm> (tablets)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe give the people to drink from the water (with the gold-dust of the golden calf)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Three different punishments were given there for three different groups. How?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did Aharon answer when Moshe asked him about the egel?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Did any of the Levi’im participate in the <glossterm>chet ha’egel</glossterm> (sin of the calf)? Proof?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe command the Levi’im to do? Why was it so difficult for the Levi’im?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Moshe’s prayer was already accepted (see 32:14); why did he have to plead for them again? (see 32:30.)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What explanation (or cause) did Moshe offer to Hashem for this great sin?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">In the parable in Rashi for above why does it say that “He gave him food and drink” (i.e., the father gave to the son)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Moshe said, “Erase me from Your book.” Why? What did Hashem answer?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did Hashem make the nation’s punishment easier? Why was He sending an angel with them?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“<emphasis role="bold">Go up</emphasis> from here.” (33:1) Why is ‘up’ used here? (Two reasons.)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why are only <emphasis role="bold">six</emphasis> nations mentioned here? Who was the seventh? Where was he?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What reason did Hashem give for not wanting to lead them?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“And the people heard <emphasis role="bold">this bad thing</emphasis>,” etc. (33:4) Which thing? How did they react?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How long does Hashem’s anger last? Who tried to use it against the Jews?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What immediate punishment did they get?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe remove his tent from the camp? How far did he move?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What name did Moshe give his tent? Who usually came to see him there?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Who else, besides the Jewish people, came to see Moshe? Proof?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did the people do when seeing Moshe leave the camp? Any parallel today?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did the people do <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> Moshe arrived at his tent? Why?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">During which period did Moshe hear Hashem’s voice at <emphasis role="bold">his</emphasis> tent? Why not afterwards?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“And he returned to the camp.” (33:11) Why did he have to <emphasis role="bold">return</emphasis>? (Two reasons.)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe request in pesukim 33:12-13? What was the response?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe request after the first response of Hashem? What else did Moshe ask? What was the response?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Then Moshe asked another favor. What? What was the answer to him?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe learn from this answer? Do we use it? When?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What special promise did Moshe get concerning the 13 Attributes of Mercy?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What was the reason given why Moshe couldn’t see all he wanted to see?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Is Hashem in the world or is the world in Hashem? What Name of Hashem tells us this?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">From what Moshe saw we learn that Hashem ‘puts on tefillin.’ How?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe get rich? How were the second Luchos different than the first?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">In the mashal that Rashi brings (34:1), who are the maids? Who is the bride?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How was the <emphasis role="bold">giving</emphasis> of the second Luchos different than the giving of the first? Why? What kind of proper
                behavior do we derive from here?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is Hashem mentioned twice in the 13 Attributes of Mercy? Explain. Why the need for mercy before the sin?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Explain the following (two meanings): <emphasis role="italic">notzer chesed la’alafim; noseh avon vafesha; vechatah; venakeh; lo
                    yenakeh</emphasis>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Prove that the <glossterm>midoh tovah</glossterm> is <emphasis role="bold">500 times</emphasis> greater than the <glossterm>midoh
                        poranius</glossterm>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When do children get punished for the parents’ sins?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">After Moshe heard the 13 Attributes of Mercy, what request did he make? What was the response?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is eating from the idol sacrifices considered so terrible?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why is there a commandment to chop of the head of a firstborn donkey (sometimes)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“They shouldn’t come empty handed to see me.” (34:20) What are the two meanings here?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">“And you shall rest from plowing and harvesting.” What does this teach us about Shabbos? What other interpretation is there concerning the laws
                of the seventh year (Shmittah)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why are some prohibitions (and mitzvos) repeated several times in the Torah?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">What promise is given to those who go up to the Beis Hamikdash for the holidays (<glossterm>Yom Tov aliyas haregel</glossterm>)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Prove that chicken with milk is not prohibited from the Torah.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How do we know that it’s forbidden to write down <glossterm>Torah Shebe’al Peh</glossterm> (Oral Law)? Then why do we have Mishna, Gemora,
                Shulchon Oruch?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How do we see the strong destructive power of sin? Where did Moshe get his holy light rays?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe use a mask? How did he teach the Torah to the Jewish people?</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <bridgehead>Extra</bridgehead>
            <orderedlist startingnumber="100">
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When else do we read the first part of this parsha?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When do we recite the pesukim of <glossterm>veshomru</glossterm> (31:16)?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When do we read (from the Torah) pesukim 34:1-10? Why?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">When do we read pesukim 33:12-34:10?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">How many mitzvos are written in this parsha, positive and negative?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Yehoshua know what was going on at the camp?</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Which <glossterm>Yomim Tovim</glossterm> (holidays) are <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> mentioned in this parsha? Why?</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
</section>
