<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="mishpatim" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Mishpatim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And these are the laws,” etc. What are the <emphasis role="bold">two</emphasis> connections to the previous parsha (Yisro)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is the term <glossterm>Shulchon Oruch</glossterm> mentioned in the first posuk? (See Rashi.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is wrong with bringing a dispute to the non-Jewish courts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the <glossterm>eved Ivri</glossterm> (Jewish slave) purchased? Would the law be different if he sold himself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of eved can get a <glossterm>shifcha Cnaanis</glossterm> (a gentile maidservant)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to this shifcha Cnaanis after the eved goes free? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if the eved Ivri refuses to leave until after six years?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can an <glossterm>eved nirtza</glossterm> be a slave forever? Until when? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which ear is pierced? Why the <emphasis role="bold">ear</emphasis> (not the nose)? (Different reasons for different <glossterm>avodim</glossterm>,
                slaves).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The door and the door post are connected with piercing the ears. How? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kind of child may the father sell into temporary slavery? Can a mother sell too?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do non-Jewish slaves (men and women) go free from slavery?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a young girl go free from slavery? (Three or four ways.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these terms: <glossterm>yi’ud</glossterm>, <glossterm>simanim</glossterm>, <glossterm>naarus</glossterm>, <glossterm>bagrus</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>sha’ir</glossterm>, <glossterm>kesus</glossterm>, <glossterm>onah</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two laws in the punishment for killing do we derive from posuk 12?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does Hashem make it happen that one person should kill another? Find a parallel to this thought in <glossterm>Pirkei Avos</glossterm> (Ethics of our
                Fathers).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a doctor mistakenly kills his patient or a father his son are they punished? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason would you give a doctor not to operate on his parents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which person gets the death penalty just for saying some words?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of thief gets punished by death?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of payments are required if one maimed a person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these terms: <glossterm>nezek</glossterm>, <glossterm>tzaar</glossterm>, <glossterm>ripui</glossterm>, <glossterm>sheves</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>boshes</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the master (or a stranger) kills a non-Jewish slave, what is his punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one kills a pregnant woman, what is his punishment? What if she survived the attack?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“An eye for an eye,” etc. How do we prove that it means monetary payment? (See Gemora Baba Kama p. 84.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The knocking out of a eye or a tooth sets a slave free. Which other limbs do the same?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If someone’s lion (or chicken) kills a person, what happens to the animal? What happens to the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person’s ox kills another ox what happens to the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the terms: <glossterm>mazik</glossterm>, <glossterm>nizak</glossterm>, <glossterm>tam</glossterm>, <glossterm>mu’od</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>kofer</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person makes a pit (<glossterm>bor</glossterm>), which kind of damages is he responsible for?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">
        For which kind of stealing does the thief pay 4 times as much? 5 times? Why this difference?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> If a thief who dug into a home gets killed by the owner, is there a punishment? Why? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> What happens to a person whose fire went and damaged others’ property? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> If animals went and trampled or ate someone’s grain, who pays for it? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> If a <glossterm>shomer khinom</glossterm> claims the article was stolen, what happens to
                him? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> In the case of a <glossterm>shomer sokhor</glossterm>, when is he held responsible? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> A person who is a <glossterm>sho’eil</glossterm> (one who borrowed), could he ever be
                exempt from payment? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"> What about a person who rents a tool from someone (a <glossterm>soicher</glossterm>), how
                is he responsible? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">
                For which kind of worship-of-idols does one get the death penalty?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of prohibitions are written concerning a <glossterm>gair</glossterm> (convert)?
                Reason?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the punishments for the mistreatment of orphans and widows? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are the priorities for <emphasis role="bold">lending money</emphasis>? What two
                prohibitions are connected with it? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What comparison is made between the soul (<glossterm>neshamah</glossterm>) at night and
                taking a pledge? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is the <glossterm>din</glossterm> of <glossterm>modeh b’miktzas</glossterm> (partial
                admission) derived from? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the warnings given about <glossterm>bikurim</glossterm> (first fruits) ,
                    <glossterm>terumah</glossterm> and <glossterm>ma’aser</glossterm>? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the <glossterm>din</glossterm> of <glossterm>pidyon ha’ben</glossterm> (redemption of
                the first born) mentioned here again? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And <emphasis role="bold">holy people</emphasis> you shall be unto Me…”, etc. How do we
                become holy? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that Hashem does not diminish the reward of any creature? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Within the same Posuk are contained warnings to a judge, and about <glossterm>loshon
                    ho’ro</glossterm>. What are they? What is the connection between these two? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we need a majority of one judge and when is a majority of two necessary for a
                verdict? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The non-Jews (idol worshippers) are in the majority, while we are the minority. Why don’t we
                follow them? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a prohibition, against treating a poor man <emphasis role="bold">too
                    well</emphasis>? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is an “enemy” mentioned by the Mitzvah of Prikah (unloading)? When are you exempt? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After a verdict when do we return the defendant for rejudgement and when not? Why? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the punishments of a judge who takes bribes to judge <emphasis role="bold"
                    >correctly</emphasis>? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which entire year is called ‘Shabbos’? Why? Do we still keep in it the regular Shabbos?
                Source? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It was said that one who uses <emphasis role="bold">forbidden conveniences on
                    Shabbos</emphasis> claiming that he <emphasis role="bold">enjoys it</emphasis> is compared to an ox.
                How? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How should one avoid any references to idols in giving travel directions? In partnerships? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What names are given here to the holidays of <glossterm>Pesach</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>Shavous</glossterm>, and <glossterm>Sukkos</glossterm>? Why? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which warnings are given here about the <glossterm>Korban Pesach</glossterm>? About
                    <glossterm>bikurim</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the Torah write three times “don’t cook the goat in its mother’s milk”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“… Behold I am sending an <emphasis role="bold">Angel</emphasis>…”, et. Why? What warning is
                given here in that connection (in the next Posuk)? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the last Parsha here was actually said before Mattan Torah, what does it mean “all the
                laws”? “and Moshe wrote down all the words of Hashem”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Sages said: “from here we know that our ancestors entered the covenant with Milah,
                T’vilo, and sprinkling of blood”. How do we know? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What “sights” did the elders see? Did they get punished for it? When? Why? Which five words
                in the Posuk tell us this? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Reb S’adya Gaon find in the Ten Commandments? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Yehoshua mentioned here? And why Khur? Where was Moshe called to?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the opinions about the six days that Moshe was covered by the cloud? Why was Moshe
                called on the seventh day? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why so we read Parshas Sh’kolim this Shabbos? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was obligated to give <glossterm>machatzis ha’shekel</glossterm>? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were these Sh’kolim used for at the Mishkon? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we have any Minhag of <glossterm>machatzis ha’shekel</glossterm> today? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Usually each person gives according to his ability. Why not <emphasis role="bold"
                    >here</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many Torahs are taken out this Shabbos? Why? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which portion is the Parshas Sh’kolim found? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the (general) content of the Haftoiroh for this Shabbos? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are the <emphasis role="bold">other three</emphasis> special Parshios we will read (on
                other Shabbosim)? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special saying of our sages describes our mood this month (get to know the Hebrew
                words)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is this month more special than other months? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is Rosh Chodesh? How many days of Rosh Chodesh? </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
