<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="pekudei" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Pekudei</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which things are being counted in this parsha? Why were they counted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word ‘Mishkan’ mentioned twice in the first posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the Mishkan a ‘testimony,’ proof, to the Jewish people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The work of Levi’im,” etc. How is this connected to the count?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Issamar? What was his position?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say, “Betzalel did all that <emphasis role="bold">Hashem</emphasis> commanded him,” rather than saying he did all that <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Moshe</emphasis> commanded him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe compliment Betzalel, saying, “You were in the shadow of Hashem”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many <glossterm>moneh</glossterm> does a regular <glossterm>kikar</glossterm> hold? A ‘holy’ kikar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we get a number (count) of 100 kikar plus 1775 shekalim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which adonim were made of silver and which of copper?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“They made the <glossterm>bigdei serod</glossterm>,” etc. Prove that this does not refer to <glossterm>bigdei kehuna</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where did the Kohein Gadol put on the head tefillin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And they brought the Mishkan to Moshe.” What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why couldn’t ordinary people put up the Mishkan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe get the special privilege to put up the Mishkan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Moshe blessed them,” etc. What blessing did he give them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we say Moshe’s blessing in davening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which day was the Mishkan put up (permanently)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was done with the shulchon, menorah, kiyor, and mizbeyach on that day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe have to do <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> the Mishkan and keilim were set up?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what capacity did Moshe serve on the eighth day of dedication? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a contradiction (between two pesukim) about Moshe’s entrance into the Mishkan. What is it? How is it resolved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that <emphasis role="bold">resting</emphasis> for the purpose of travelling is called <emphasis role="bold">travelling</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the presence of Hashem seen by day? By night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the signs to travel? To rest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we say ‘Chazak’ at the end of <emphasis role="bold">this</emphasis> parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Mishkan work was finished in the month of Kislev. Why was its dedication postponed for Nissan? Did Kislev ever get to celebrate this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there any connection between parshas Pekudei and the month of Adar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special parsha do we read for maftir? Why? What are the other three parshiyos (from the set of ‘four parshiyos’)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Extra</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="30">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what way was the Mishkan superior to the first and second Beis Hamikdash?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it describe how the gold threads were made? (See Sforno 38:21-22, Rambam 39:3.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The <glossterm>avneit</glossterm> (belt) had shatnez in it. Who wore it? (See Rashbam 39:29.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Bnei Yisroel did,” etc. (39:42) But they didn’t all do it? Explain. (See Ohr Hachayim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it repeated <emphasis role="bold">three times</emphasis> that the people did the work? (See Kli Yakar 39:42-43.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“As Hashem commanded Moshe,” etc. Why is this repeated so many times? (See Baal Haturim at the end of the parsha.)</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
