<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="tetzaveh" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Tetzaveh</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What commandment is given in the first posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which process was used to extract the olive oil for the menorah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which oil was kosher for a <glossterm>Korban Minchah</glossterm> but not for the menorah? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the word <glossterm>tamid</glossterm> (steadily) interpreted in the halachos of the menorah differently than in the halachos of the
                    <glossterm>lechem hapanim</glossterm> (showbread)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much oil was poured into the menorah every night? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many garments did the <glossterm>Kohein Gadol</glossterm> (High Priest) wear? Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the five materials from which the garments were made?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the special garments of <glossterm>choshen</glossterm> and <glossterm>eifod</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the word <glossterm>kehuna</glossterm> (or Kohein) mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was inscribed on the two <glossterm>shoham</glossterm> stones? What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many <emphasis role="bold">letters</emphasis> were inscribed in each stone?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which way did one of the names on these stones differ from the regular count? In which <emphasis role="bold">order</emphasis> were they
                listed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which three names of tribes did <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> appear on these stones? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the <glossterm>choshen <emphasis role="bold">hamishpot</emphasis></glossterm> called by that name? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of precious stones were installed in the choshen hamishpot?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the <glossterm>urim v’tumim</glossterm>? Where were they inserted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the second Beis Hamikdash did they have the choshen? Complete? What other differences were there in the keilim of the second?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was attached to the choshen that caused Aharon to announce his arrival? What lesson in good manners could be learned from it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the <glossterm>tzitz</glossterm>? Who wore it? When? It also has a second name. What is it? The Gemora learns out a <glossterm>din</glossterm>
                (law) about tefillin from the <glossterm>tzitz</glossterm>. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The tzitz brought Hashem’s forgiveness for certain sins. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are two opinions about the meaning of <glossterm>tamid</glossterm> written in connection with the tzitz. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many garments did a regular Kohein wear? What were they? Did they wear a tzitz? Did they wear <glossterm>shatnez</glossterm> (mixture of wool and
                linen)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Kohein is missing a garment, can he serve? What if he does? What were some other prohibitions in the service of the Kohanim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which korbanos were brought for the ‘inauguration’ dedication of the Kohanim? How was the <glossterm>shemen hamishcho</glossterm> used for the
                Kohanim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the flour offerings that were brought?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of the <glossterm>par</glossterm> (ox) brought for an atonement? How was its treatment different than other kinds of
                    <glossterm>Korban Chatos</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint about the future death of Aharon’s two sons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was done with the rams after they were slaughtered?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of ‘waving’ the four sacrifices? Any resemblance to the waving of the <glossterm>lulov</glossterm> (four species)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is first in line to succeed the Kohein Gadol? What if he can’t?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the mizbeyach need atonement?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the mizbeyach sanctified for service? Was oil used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which animals are not kosher for korbanos? Which become <glossterm>posul</glossterm>
                <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> they’re brought?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the ‘inner mizbeyach’ made differently than the regular mizbeyach? What was it used for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It is said that this parsha is the only one not to mention Hashem’s name. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which sedra is parshas Zachor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which phrase in parshas Zachor is repeated twice by the reader? How? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
