<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="vayakhel" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayakhel</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Moshe gathered,” etc. On which day did this happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was the warning about Shabbos written before other things?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t kindle fire,” etc. Why is this <glossterm>melacha</glossterm> (work) singled out?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the commandments about the Mishkan works repeated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which roof covers are called ‘Mishkan,’ which ‘its tent,’ and which ‘its cover’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did they need <emphasis role="bold">wise</emphasis> people to produce the oil for the menorah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the special wisdom of the women in weaving goats’ wool?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the <glossterm>nesiyim</glossterm> (heads of tribes; princes) bring? When? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the nesiyim the first to bring things for the mizbeyach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is their title (nesiyim) written without the letter <emphasis role="italic">yud</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that in the presence of Hashem there is no difference between the high <glossterm>shevatim</glossterm> (tribes) and the lowest one.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What strange announcement did Moshe command to announce in the camp?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many adonim and how many yados were there per keresh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Betzalel made the aron,” etc. Did he personally make it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The order of the Mishkan work is different here than in parshas Terumah. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special contribution did the women bring for the kiyor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Moshe happy to accept it? Why? What did Hashem say to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was the women’s contribution used for the kiyor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which items that were needed for the <glossterm>avodah</glossterm> (service) are not mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which woods were covered with silver?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Extra</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="21">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the dimensions of the following: <glossterm>mizbeyach ha’olah</glossterm>, <glossterm>mizbeyach hazahav</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>aron</glossterm>, <glossterm>shulchon</glossterm>, <glossterm>menorah</glossterm>, <glossterm>kiyor</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the prohibition against fire on Shabbos mentioned here? (See Sforno, Rambam.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe have to <emphasis role="bold">gather</emphasis> the people <emphasis role="bold">here</emphasis>? (See 0hr Hachayim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it mention that the men came to give jewelry <emphasis role="bold">with the women</emphasis>? (See Sforno 2, Kli Yakar.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the Jewish community went out,” etc. Why is this mentioned here? (See Ohr Hachayim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the nesiyim brought,” etc. Who are these nesiyim according to the Gemora?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Betzalel related to Moshe? (See Rashi, Daas Zekenim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Moshe said: Look! Hashem called the name,” etc. (35:30) Why did he say that? (See Baal Haturim, Daas Zekenim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And to <emphasis role="bold">teach</emphasis> He gave into his heart” etc. (35:34). Why is this emphasized? (See Ebn Ezra, Ohr Hachayim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Betzalel made the aron.” Is that the only thing he made? (See Daas Zekenim.)</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Parshas Shekalim, Rosh Chodesh Adar, etc.</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="31">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many <emphasis role="bold">special</emphasis> parshiyos do we read between now and Pesach? What are their names?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we read parshas Shekalim on this Shabbos? Which part do we read?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the source and reason for the saying, ‘<emphasis role="italic">Mi shenichnas Adar marbin b’simcha</emphasis>’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many Sifrei Torah will be used in shul this Shabbos? How many <glossterm>aliyos</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the month of Adar the Beis Din in Eretz Yisroel was concerned with <glossterm>kilayim</glossterm>. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Certain kinds of disputes should be resolved this month. Which kind? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why must it be <emphasis role="bold">half</emphasis> a shekel? Do we give it today? What did Hashem show to Moshe?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
