<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="yisro" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Yisro</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Yisro heard,” etc. What exactly did he hear?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were Yisro’s other (six) names? Reasons? (Give three.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Moshe’s family in Midyan, and not in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the reasons for the names Gershom and Eliezer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Paroh ever attempt to use a sword against Moshe? What happened?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it emphasized that Yisro came to the <emphasis role="bold">desert</emphasis> (<glossterm>midbar</glossterm>)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Yisro arrive before or after <glossterm>Matan Torah</glossterm> (the Giving of the Torah)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Yisro happy to hear about the downfall of the Egyptians? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What’s a famous saying about converts (<glossterm>geirim</glossterm>)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Only a person like Yisro could have made such a statement about faith. Which statement?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Aharon, the elders and Yisro were eating together. Where was Moshe?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proof that the part about judges does not appear in chronological order?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was bothering Yisro about Moshe’s system of justice?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which qualities did Yisro require for judges to have?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which day did they arrive at <glossterm>Har Sinai</glossterm> (Mount Sinai)? What mood were they in?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Hashem’s care of Bnei Yisroel compared to the way an eagle cares for his young?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">‘All beginnings are hard.’ Where in the parsha is this idea applicable?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You shall be unto Me a nation of priests.” But Kohanim came from only one tribe? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that all of the blind (and the deaf, etc.) were healed.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Moshe add an extra day of preparation on his own?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Jewish nation was (and is) compared to a <emphasis role="bold">disciple</emphasis> and to a <emphasis role="bold">bride</emphasis>. Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Hashem speak from Heaven or from Har Sinai? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the Kohanim and the people shouldn’t go up,” etc. Were there ‘Kohanim’ then?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was unusual about Moshe’s voice when he was saying the eight commandments to the nation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Were Moshe, Aharon, and the ‘Kohanim’ standing together? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the people respond to each commandment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Hashem begin by saying “I. . . am the <emphasis role="bold">One Who took you out from Mitzrayim</emphasis>”? (Three reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the idols called ‘other’ deities? How does the Tanya explain it? (See Ch. 22.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Hashem’s good measure is 500 times greater than His harsh measure.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the Ten Commandments (<glossterm>Aseres Hadibros</glossterm>), where do we apply the twelfth method of interpretation that is taught by Rabbi
                Yishmael?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why can’t we use iron in the building of the <glossterm>mizbeyach</glossterm> (altar)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Matan Torah a greater experience than all other miracles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When else do we read (most of) parshas Yisro other than on Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Find an <emphasis role="bold">obvious</emphasis> connection between the parsha and the portions of Tanya that we often learn this same week.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were such “simple” instructions chosen to be included in the 10 commandments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which way were the Bnai Yisroel compared to Yisro at Mattan Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which day of the week was the Torah given? How do we mention it on that day?
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
