<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
            <para dir="ltr">THE CHUMASH QUESTIONS</para>
            <para dir="ltr">A workbook for the weekly sedra</para>
            <para dir="ltr">based on the commentary of Rashi</para>
            <para dir="ltr">BY RABBI DOVID WICHNIN</para>
            <para dir="ltr">© 1995 Morristown, NJ</para>
            <para dir="ltr"> All Rights Reserved.</para>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-4e2d6bae-b3eb-49bd-67f9-1fb55ee880fd">
            <para dir="ltr">Tis puélimtz'on dedicated to</para>
            <para dir="ltr">te Luavitcer ee</para>
            <para dir="ltr">to wbam the mat/302;</para>
            <para dir="ltr">5M avid Wanin,</para>
            <para dir="ltr">was ekusbar</para>
            <para dir="ltr">with weryfier a 19 ein an wose slier he Carrie out</para>
            <para dir="ltr">with re uost devotimz.</para>
        </emphasis></para>
    <para>\</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-4e2d6bae-b3ec-ed63-177f-e1bf16c8ed1f"><para dir="ltr">GENT</para><para dir="ltr">The inspiration and continued support
                for this project has come from: Mr. and Mrs. Yosef Chaim Lester</para><para dir="ltr">Managing editor Pessy Leah Lester</para><para dir="ltr">Typing Devorah
                Hott</para><para dir="ltr">Copy editing, design, typesetting Yael Resnick</para><para dir="ltr">Editorial consultant Rabbi Zaiman Wilschanski</para><para dir="ltr"
                >Consultants Rabbi Zalman Dubinsky Rabbi Yeheskel Lebovic Rabbi Avraham Lipskier Yisroel N oach Wichnin</para><para dir="ltr">PhOtO com-fies); of Albie
                Rosenhaus</para><para dir="ltr">Cover design Yael Resnick</para><para dir="ltr">Special thanks to; Sara Arno Rus Devorah Burdmam</para><para dir="ltr">Copyright ©
                1995 Mrs. M. Wiclvmin All Rights Reserved.</para><para dir="ltr">possiék in great measure 6y a generous donation .g. ....r w "
        "</para>\u000C</emphasis>\u0000</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-4e2d6bae-b3ec-a050-2879-2334d3dfd5db"><para dir="ltr">A I '10</para><para dir="ltr">1938—1995</para><para dir="ltr"
                >Rabbi, teacher, mentor, counselor, guide, mashpia. Which word best describes Rabbi Dovid Wichnin, 22”}? All</para><para dir="ltr">of the above and more, In a word,
                he was a Chossid of the Rebbe striving to carry out his shlichus.</para><para dir="ltr">For 18 years, Rabbi David</para><para dir="ltr">Wichnin was the Rosh
                Yeshiva</para><para dir="ltr">of the Rabbinical College of</para><para dir="ltr">America’s Yeshiva Tiferes</para><para dir="ltr">Bachurim in Morristown, N], one of
                the largest yeshivas in America for baalei teshuva (Iews who have returneé to the Iudaism of their ancestors) T. With humor, discipline and love, Rabbi Wiclmin
                taught and; guided thousands of students over the years. Students remember Rabbi Wichnin as both a tough and compassionate teacher and role~modei "who lead the
                yeshiva with exuberance.</para>He also helped hundreds more as the rabbi of the Tzemach Tzedek </emphasis>\u0000</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-4e2d6bae-b3ec-3978-fb3a-d8c55151deb3">
            <para dir="ltr">shul in Monsey, NY, where he 1ived with his wife and three children. He was sought out often for marital advice and performed imeasura‘ole acts of
                kindness (often in secret), and carried out the mivtzoyz'm (mitzvah campaigns) of the Lubavitcher Rebbe.</para>
            <para dir="ltr">Chaim Dovid Nota Wichnin was born in 1938 in Bobroisk, White Russia, to Rabbi Nachman Dov and Faigy. Not long after his birth, his family fled to
                southeastern Russiar—as did many Lubavitcher Chassidim during World War II-wto escape the Nazis. In the Winter of 1941, his mothér and sister Hinda died in
                Samarkand, Russia. In 1946, he and his father fled from Russia, through Poland and Austria until they arrived in France. He remained in Paris where he attended
                Yeshiva until 1951.</para>
            <para dir="ltr">In 1951, Rabbi Wichnin and his father immigrated to Canada, settling in Montreal. He learned at the Lubavitch Yeshiva in</para>
        </emphasis></para>
    <para>\u0000</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-4e2d6bae-b3ec-009a-fa14-b94bcfce5234">
            <para dir="ltr">Montreal Where he began to demonstrate his brilliance as a Torah scholar. In 1962 he received smicha (rabbinical ordination) from the Rabbinical College
                of Canada’s Yeshiva Tomchei Temimim in Montreal.</para>
            <para dir="ltr">In 1965, he began a long career as an educator when he took a position as a teacher at Central High School for Girls in Brooklyn, NY, where he taught
                until 1972. He moved to Brookline, Mass, in 1972, Where he became principal of the New England Hebrew Day Academy until 1977. While living in Brookline, Rabbi
                Wichnin became a favorite of Rav Yosef Dov Soloveitchik, 2”}, the late Torah authority and leader. In 1977 Rabbi Wichnin took on a new challenge, joining the staff
                of Tiferes Bachurim in Morristown where he helped establish it as a first-rate Torah learning center.</para>
        </emphasis></para>
    <para>\u0000</para>
</section>
