<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="balak" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Balak</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Balak saw,” etc. What did he see that scared him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We know that Moav and Midyan (nations) were enemies. Why were they at peace?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Even so, why did Moav decide to ask the elders of Midyan for advice?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Balak was said to be a temporary ruler. Why? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And why was a non-Jew given the power of prophecy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did this prophet (Bilam) accomplish for the nations?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Balak describe the Jewish nation and its threat to Bilam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the praise that Balak gave Bilam at the outset?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the elders of Moav and Midyan bring along tools for magic?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the elders of Midyan left early because Bilam failed their test.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">To Bilam (and his kind) prophecy appears at night. Why? To whom else did it happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Bilam hated the Jewish people more strongly than Balak.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What example from a bee is used to explain the answer to Bilam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What answer and reason did Bilam give to the elders of Moav? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Balak respond to this refusal of Bilam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">a) Why did Bilam think he deserved <emphasis role="bold">a full house</emphasis> of gold and silver?</para>
            <para dir="ltr">b) Find the opinion of the Mishna in Pirkei Avos 5:19 on this subject.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Bilam told in prophecy the second night? Still he went. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of (similar) behavior is caused by either extreme of love or hate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When did Bilam admit that he could not do anything on his own?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was it an angry angel or a merciful one who stopped Bilam from going?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many people must accompany an important person’s trip? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the donkey see the angel and Bilam didn’t?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the angel carry a sword against Bilam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the donkey do when she saw the angel the first, second, and third time? What happened to Bilam’s foot?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the angel change his positions three times? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“If I had a sword,” etc. Why was this an embarrassing statement for Bilam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the donkey say to Bilam when he hit her? What did he answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam do when he was given permission to see the angel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the angel do to the donkey? Why? Another example for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When Bilam apologized to the angel he admitted another embarrassing fact about himself. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In Bilam’s offer to return, excuse, and complaint, he used an example from Avrohom Avinu. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Finally the angel told him to go ahead. What do we learn from it concerning a person’s choice of behavior?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Balak arranged to meet Bilam in his <emphasis role="bold">metropolis</emphasis> twice?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Balak and Bilam offer <emphasis role="bold">seven</emphasis> sacrifices on <emphasis role="bold">seven</emphasis> altars?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Balak get a daytime prophecy <emphasis role="bold">here</emphasis> (but never before)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the need in mentioning Yaakov and Yisroel in the planned curses?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Bilam asked how he could curse if G-d didn’t curse them. What are the historic examples when the Jews were deserving of curses but didn’t get
                them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam mean when he said, “But Hashem didn’t get angry at them”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we learn here about Bilam’s special power for cursing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does he compare our early foundations to rocks and hills?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And among the nations he is not counted.” What is meant here? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam mean when he said, “Who counted Yaakov’s sand”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Balak was better at certain types of magic than Bilam.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 23:18, what proves Bilam’s anger at Balak? Cause of anger?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Bilam explained to Balak that Hashem is not like a human, how?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does Hashem relate to us when we do aveiros?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Because there is no witchcraft in Yaakov,” etc. What is the reward for this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A time will come, according to Bilam’s prophecy, that the Jewish nation will be superior to the angels. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there no need for witchcraft among our nation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which one did Bilam compare us to lions? (AM and PM.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What prophecy of doom did Bilam hint at about himself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What qualities did Bilam notice by looking at their tents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Both Balak and Bilam were greater than their fathers. How? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the three bad traits that Bilam had?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Bilam fall down whenever Hashem appeared to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to the Midrash which mishkanos was Bilam praising?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did he praise them? And the praise for the (destroyed) Beis Hamikdash?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to posuk 24:6 how did he describe the tents and tabernacles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam mean by saying, “His king will be higher than Agag,” etc.?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What will happen to those who bless the Jewish people? And the reverse?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Balak say to Bilam after he clapped his hands in anger?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam reply, and what final advice did he give to Balak?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Bilam predict about King David? About Rome?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what way was Amalek the <emphasis role="bold">first</emphasis> among the nations? What’s his <emphasis role="bold">end</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Bilam wondering about the Keini (Yisro’s descendants)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">With whom were the Keini exiled? What is their destiny?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that through immoral relationships one may come to worship idols. What question did Pinchas ask Moshe? What did Moshe forget? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By which rule did Moshe send Pinchas to do his mitzvoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which posuk from Bilam’s prophecy is included in our daily davening?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
