<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="chukas" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Chukas</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word <glossterm>chukah</glossterm> mentioned here? What are the two categories of mitzvos called?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many black hairs disqualify a <glossterm>para adumah</glossterm> (red heifer)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And <emphasis role="bold">he</emphasis> shall slaughter it in front of <emphasis role="bold">him</emphasis>.” Who does it? In front of whom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Elazar do it (not Aharon)? Where was it slaughtered?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which direction was the sprinkling of the blood done? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The ashes (mixed with water) of the para adumah were divided in three parts. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which body (in death) contains the strongest impurity (tumah)? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When can a person who became tomei enter the Mishkan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What else was burned along with the rest of the para adumah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the paradox (contradictory case) in this mitzvoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which people are said to be tomei until the evening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For how long does a person who touches a dead body become tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does he become cleansed? Can one become tomei without <emphasis role="bold">touching</emphasis> a <glossterm>meis</glossterm> (dead body)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">One who <emphasis role="bold">touches</emphasis> the water (mixed with ashes) is tamei differently. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is called <glossterm>Avi Avos Hatumah</glossterm>? <glossterm>Av Hatumah</glossterm>? <glossterm>Rishon</glossterm>?
                <glossterm>Sheini</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to Reb Moshe Hadarshon, what is the symbolism in the following:</para>
        <orderedlist numeration="upperalpha">
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why did the Jews pay for the para adumah?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why does it have to be a cow?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why a <emphasis role="bold">red</emphasis> one?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why unblemished?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why shouldn’t it have had a yoke?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why does it have to be done by one next-to-the-highest Kohein?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why is it burned?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Aharon himself do it?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why the <emphasis role="bold">three</emphasis> species?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why take cedar wood?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why a lowly bush?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why is one third put away for <emphasis role="bold">safekeeping for later generations</emphasis>?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why do those who work with it become tomei?</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para dir="ltr">Why do its ashes bring cleanliness?</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Miriam’s death written here? Which year was it (of their stay in the desert)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that their water supply in the desert was in the merit of Miriam.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Hashem is concerned about the safety of our possessions</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special neis happened around the ‘water-stone’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why couldn’t Moshe and Aharon find the stone which used to give water?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe and Aharon get angry at the people? What name did they call them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe and Aharon hit the stone <emphasis role="bold">twice</emphasis>? Were they ever told to hit (a stone)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Torah <emphasis role="bold">states the reason</emphasis> for Moshe and Aharon’s loss of privilege to go to Eretz Yisroel. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There was a bigger mistake that Moshe committed earlier. What was it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Moshe punished for it? Why? Why was he punished for the smaller one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe and Aharon missed an opportunity for Kiddush Hashem. What was it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And He was <emphasis role="bold">sanctified by them</emphasis>.” How? Where else did this happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Egyptians did foresee something like this. How? What was their error?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“So said your <emphasis role="bold">brother</emphasis> Yisroel,” etc. Why did they mention <emphasis role="bold">brotherhood</emphasis> here (to
                Edom)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Eisov leave Yaakov and go his own way? Where did Yaakov go?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that deceased parents (the Avos) suffer in the grave when the children are in trouble.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special blessing that Yaakov got from his father helps our prayers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Nevi’im are called <glossterm>malochim</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why <emphasis role="bold">shouldn’t</emphasis> Edom be upset that the Jews (but not Edom) are getting Eretz Yisroel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe made an <emphasis role="bold">offer</emphasis> to Edom for letting the people pass through his land. Was it a good offer? How did Edom respond?
                Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What mode of proper conduct do we derive from Moshe’s offer to Edom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was Edom demonstrating the use of his blessing with confidence?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Aharon was buried on a double mountain. But weren’t all mountains levelled?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who went up to the mountain together with Aharon and Moshe? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Take Aharon,” etc. How was Moshe supposed to do that?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe wish upon observing Aharon’s passing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the whole community saw,” etc. How was Aharon’s death seen by all?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was there a need to show it to everybody?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The entire house of Israel cried,” etc. Why the <emphasis role="bold">whole house</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Find the saying of the Mishna, in Pirkei Avos, based on the above verse.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After Aharon’s passing, the Jews were attacked by a disguised enemy. Who?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was there a problem about praying for victory? How was it resolved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the people getting worried and impatient when circling the land of Edom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was their specific complaint about the mon? And about the Exodus?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were <emphasis role="bold">snakes</emphasis> sent upon them? How did the people react?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that when asked, a person <emphasis role="bold">should</emphasis> forgive the wrongs done to him.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which remedy did Hashem advise Moshe to prepare for them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did our Sages explain the workings of this remedy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the miracles done at the streams of Arnon? What comparison is given?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Hashem’s name not mentioned in ‘The Song of the Well’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the water from the well delivered to each tribe? Why is the subject of the well mentioned here? Where can the well be seen today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And <emphasis role="bold">Israel</emphasis> sent messengers,” etc. (21:21) And somewhere else it says that <emphasis role="bold">Moshe</emphasis> sent
                (these) messengers. What do we learn from this change?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Sichon, the King of Cheshbon, opposed to letting the Jews pass through?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What great miracle did Hashem arrange for the victory of Bnei Yisroel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Because the border of Amon is (too) strong,” etc. Why was it so strong?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it mentioned here that Sichon fought with the King of Moav?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was the ‘team’ that helped Sichon conquer Moav? What life is given to them here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The people that were sent to spy in the land of Yaazer were brave. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Moshe afraid to fight a war with King Og of Boshon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What can we learn from the above concerning our conduct?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do you know what happened in Russia on the 12th and the 13th days of Tamuz, 1927?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
