<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="korach" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Korach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Korach took,” etc. What did he take? (Two explanations.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Whose name is not mentioned with Korach’s ancestors? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Korach’s children survived.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which tribe helped Korach most? Why? What is the saying about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which appointment of leadership angered Korach the most? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">I Why does this parsha follow the (ending of the) previous one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Moshe heard and fell on his face.” Why didn’t he pray?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Some ‘kal vachomer’ approaches are wrong. Korach had one. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The whole community <emphasis role="bold">is holy</emphasis>,” etc. What did Korach mean by this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What other objection did Korach have Moshe’s appointments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe suggest to wait until the morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe suggested that they offer ketores. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Korach dare undertake such great risks?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe saw something in the future which Korach didn’t. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe first speak softly to Korach, then spoke harshly to <emphasis role="bold">all</emphasis> Levi’im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe answer to Korach’s objection about positions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What message did Moshe send to Dosson and Avirom? Their answers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe try so hard to explain things to all these people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not turn to their gift (offering).” Which offering? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Moshe ever have an opportunity to benefit from the nation? Did he benefit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Korach incite the people against Moshe that night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe say to Hashem, “One man sins and You are angry at everybody”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was everybody told to move away from Korach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we prove that <glossterm>machlokes</glossterm> (discord) is punished more severely than other sins.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What test Moshe propose to see who is right?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happened to Korach and his people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And what happened to the 250 who brought ketores?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did they do with fire-pans used for the ketores? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the above punishments, why did a plague come upon them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe know the method for stopping a plague?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By what power (besides ketores) did Aharon stop the plague from spreading?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the special message of using <emphasis role="bold">ketores</emphasis> to stop the plague?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of taking twelve <glossterm>kaves</glossterm> (sticks) from the tribes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon’s stick grow <emphasis role="bold">almonds</emphasis>, not other fruit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of ‘guarding’ were the Kohanim and Levi’im told to do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the parsha of <glossterm>matanos kehuna</glossterm> (gifts) written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of gifts from <emphasis role="bold">produce</emphasis> are enumerated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And gifts from <emphasis role="bold">animals</emphasis>? How about <emphasis role="bold">human</emphasis> gifts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which of these gifts is still given today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which gifts are commanded to be given to Levi’im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is <emphasis role="bold">salt</emphasis> mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is it seen here that this parsha (on gifts) is very beloved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Levi’im give any gifts to Kohanim? Was it holy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Levi took his maaser before terumah was given to the Kohein, what was he supposed to do? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which month did we bless this Shabbos? When is Rosh Chodesh? What’s special about this month in Chassidic history?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are the special tefillos for this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are especially happy days that Chassidim celebrate in this month. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are days in this month which will be happy ones as soon as Moshiach comes. Which days?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
