<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="masei" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Masei</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“These are the travels,” etc. Why are they all written here? (Give the opinions of Rabbi Moshe Hadarshon and Rabbi Tanchuma.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“On the <emphasis role="bold">morrow</emphasis> of Pesach the Jews went out” (33:3) But didn’t they leave on Pesach itself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it mention here that the Egyptians were “burying their dead,” etc.?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The original name of Midbar Paran is changed here to <glossterm>Risma</glossterm> (33:18). Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How old was Aharon when he passed away? How did he die?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the Cnaani King of Arad heard,” etc. Why is it mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many stations along their travels are mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Posuk 49 mentions the space occupied by the camping tribes. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the warning to drive out the nations from Eretz Yisroel repeated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Yehoshua repeated the same warning to Bnei Isroel. Where? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What will happen if the Jews don’t drive out their enemies?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the purpose of describing the borders of Eretz Yisroel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say, “This is the land that will <emphasis role="bold">fall</emphasis> to you,” etc?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At the time of the Exodus what could have been the shortest route from Mitzrayim to Eretz Yisroel? Why weren’t they taken along this route?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Into how many tribes was Eretz Yisroel divided? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Torah enumerates the heads of tribes that will parcel out the land for their tribe members. Which tribes are not mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The open spaces around the towns of the Levi’im were allowed to be used only for some purposes, but not for others. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What purpose did these towns serve besides residences for Levi’im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Even though Moshe set aside three cities of refuge (<glossterm>arei miklot</glossterm>), they didn’t function until later. When? Why then did Moshe set
                them up for this purpose?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The two-and-a-half tribes on the east side of <glossterm>Yarden</glossterm> (Jordan) got the same amount of cities of refuge (three) as the entire land
                of Israeli Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What might have happened if they didn’t set aside cities of refuge?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And if he killed him with an iron tool,” etc. What kind of a murder is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it not mentioned here how big the iron tool has to be, as it says for stones and wood?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In a case of unintentional killing, sometimes the killer is not exiled. When? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the avenger of the blood (<glossterm>goel hadam</glossterm>) kills the murderer outside of the cities of refuge, is he punished? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When can the murderer leave the city of refuge? Why? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What type of murderer has to wait until the death of two Kohanim Gedolim to get out? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a murderer be punished (killed) on circumstantial evidence? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is ransom mentioned in this subject?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did they have a Sanhedrin outside of Eretz Yisroel? When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there such a strong warning against making the land impure?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The heads of the Gil’ad family approached Moshe with certain concerns. What were they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Moshe’s response about Bnos Tzlafchad and other daughters that inherit parts of the land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And if the Yovel will come,” etc. What did Rabbi Yehuda learn from this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to Rashi, in what order are the daughters of Tzlafchad listed here and elsewhere?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you find a contradiction between this statement of Rashi and his comments in parshas Pinchas? How can it be resolved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The prohibition that a daughter inheriting a share of the land may not to marry out of her tribe, was not a permanent one. Explain. (Check the Rashi in
                parshas Pinchas for this halacha.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is Rosh Chodesh? What special period starts then?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
