<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Noso</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which age bracket of Levi’im were included in the count of Gershon, Kehos, Merori? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Of the above three families, which was the largest? The smallest? What were their jobs?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were three <emphasis role="bold">general categories</emphasis> of people who became tomei. What were they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From which camps were the above sent out? Until when?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person stole, then swore falsely but later admitted his sin, how does he pay?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">This subject (stealing and swearing) is repeated here for the second time. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And if the man has no relative,” etc. (5:8) Why must this refer to a <glossterm>ger</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 5:9, <glossterm>terumah</glossterm> is mentioned but Rashi interprets this as <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">bikurim</emphasis></glossterm>.
                Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which important din do we learn here about bikurim? How does that prove the rule of our sages, “the words of Torah are poor in one place and
                rich in another”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of authority does the owner (Yisroel) have on his tithes that are given away?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">One who withholds (doesn’t give) his tithes, what punishment does he get?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And what is the reward for the one who gives his tithes generously?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A woman who is unfaithful is being <emphasis role="bold">disloyal</emphasis> in a double way. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Our sages said: “A person does not sin unless he is overtaken by stupidity.” Prove it from this portion.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If this woman really committed adultery, why doesn’t she get her deserved punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the flour (for her korban) made of <emphasis role="bold">barley</emphasis> rather than wheat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove from this parsha that it is shameful for a married woman to uncover her hair.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the ingredients in the water that the <glossterm>Sotah</glossterm> drinks?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who else gets punished by her drinking if she is guilty?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to her through the drinking if she is innocent?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one become a <glossterm>Nazir</glossterm>? What is a Nazir barred from?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the subject of Nazir written next to the portion on Sotah? Can a woman be a Nazir?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to the Nazir if he becomes tomei accidentally?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And he should atone on him from his <emphasis role="bold">sins on the nefesh,</emphasis>” etc. What sin? (Two opinions.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A Nazir who concluded his period properly, what does he do at the conclusion?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Regarding the <glossterm>Birkas Kohanim</glossterm>, why is ‘saying to them’ emphasized (6:23)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the first blessing there is a positive and a negative statement. What is their content?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is Hashem’s gift different from that of a human being?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the content of the middle blessing? The third one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which word appears in all three blessings? Are all of the blessings equal in length?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where do we say this blessing in cur prayers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do Kohanim perform this mitzvoh of blessing the Jewish people? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And I shall bless them.” Whom? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the Jewish nation compared to on the day the Mishkan was erected?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“When Moshe finished putting up the Mishkan.” But others also worked on it. Who were they? Why is only Moshe mentioned? What is the comparison with King
                David?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Those who were now the heads of tribes (<glossterm>nesiyim</glossterm>), what were they doing in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the nesiyim <emphasis role="bold">the first ones</emphasis> to bring their gifts to this celebration?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who got more wagons and oxen among the Levi’im? Why? Who got none? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the two possible orders by which the nesiyim could have brought their gifts? Which one was chosen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Find an example here to the saying of the Mishna, “One mitzvoh brings another one.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who paid for these gifts, the nasi or his tribe? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“He offered. . .he offered his Korban,” etc. Why is ‘he offered’ repeated in connection with the tribe of Yissochor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What complaint did the tribe of Reuven have? What was ‘Moshe’s’ reply?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the significance of these numbers: 930, 130, 500, 20, 7O, 10?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which nasi brought his korban (gift) on Shabbos? (See Baal Haturim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the weight of the utensils mentioned separately and also together?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are two pesukim that seem to be contradictory, until a third posuk comes and resolves it. Which are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is the ‘Voice’ of Sinai mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
