<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="pinchas" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Pinchas</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it mentioned here (again) that Pinchas is the grandson of Aharon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the words of the posuk, what did Pinchas do for Hashem? For the nation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reward did Pinchas get for his brave act? (Two things.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Wasn’t Pinchas automatically a Kohein by being a grandson of Aharon? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it mentioned who Zimri’s father was and his position? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the family and position of Kozbi (the Midyanite woman) mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Only Midyan was to be punished and destroyed, not Moav. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were Moshe and Aharon commanded here to count the people? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the names of the families in each tribe written with the letters <glossterm>hai</glossterm> and <glossterm>yud</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When did Korach’s sons repent? What happened to them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many families are counted here (with Levi)? How is this number connected with the statement, “You are the smallest of all nations”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a name mentioned here even though it is not connected with a family. Whose? Why is it mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is the total number here the same as the number in parshas Bamidbor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From what age did a person get a share in the land? When was this age supposed to be reached (before or after entering the land?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By which estimates was the land partitioned into twelve sections?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was it divided among the twelve tribes? (Two methods.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is this inheritance assigned differently than a usual inheritance?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which people were not included in the lots for division (besides women)? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which person had the <glossterm>zechus</glossterm> (merit) to complete the number 70 for the Jewish people in Mitzrayim? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who wasn’t counted among the rest of the nation (only separately)? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that there were many more women than men in the nation at this time.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Five smart girls had a complaint to Moshe. Who were they? What was their complaint?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it mentioned that they were from the family of Yoseif? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the order of the girls’ names change in two places?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that their case came up on the fortieth year?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the dispute between Rabbi Yashiya and Aba Chonon here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did they have to say that their father was not among the sinners?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For what sin did he die? (Two opinions.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the girls’ proof that they should be considered like sons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Moshe have the answer for them? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that these girls saw something that Moshe didn’t see?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many portions did they get? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a special expression (for transfer) regarding a daughter’s portion?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the portion telling Moshe about his passing written here? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say, “As your brother Aharon passed away”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the order of preference for inheritance?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the Torah always mention the reason for Moshe and Aharon’s passing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe is asking about a successor. Why here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the reason for Yehoshua’s choice?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does he mention that Hashem knows everyone’s mind?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“That will go out before them.” What does it mean here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“That will take them out and bring them in.” How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How should Moshe ‘take’ Yehoshua?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How should Moshe demonstrate (in front of the people) that Yehoshua was chosen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should Moshe tell Yehoshua about the people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe have to do to put his spirit on Yehoshua?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we learn that Moshe’s face was like the sun and Yehoshua’s face like the moon? What are the Hebrew words for these?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was Moshe’s request about his own family having leadership fulfilled by this transfer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe convince Yehoshua about the greatness of this position?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe did more for Yehoshua than he was asked. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the subject of the sacrifices written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that not only Kohanim but also Levi’im and Yisroelim were to be present at the daily korban? How was their presence arranged?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we derive that the morning Tamid was to be done on the western side and the evening Tamid on the eastern side of the area designated for
                sacrifices?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The Olah that was brought at Har Sinai.” Which one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which part is called ‘My bread’? Which is ‘My korban’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two kinds of wine are not kosher for Nesochim? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one Shabbos korban is missed, can it be made up the next Shabbos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is the proper time of day for the offering of the Korban Musaf on Shabbos and Yom Tov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of sins are atoned by the Korban Musaf?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which sin is atoned by the Korban Musaf of Rosh Chodesh? (Two answers.) Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the meaning of the three types they had to bring for the Korbanos Musaf: <glossterm>porim</glossterm>, <glossterm>eilim</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>kevasim</glossterm> (bulls, rams, lambs)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By what name is the holiday of Shavuos called here? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the special order for the korbanos (bulks) on the hoiiday of Sukkos? How many were there in total?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On Sukkos, how many lambs did they bring in all? The significance of it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint about the special ‘pouring of water’ on Sukkos? What do we call it, and how do we celebrate it nowadays?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the name for the 8th day of Succos? Reasons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What the good advice does the Torah give us about the Korbonos that were donated during the
                year (<glossterm>nedorim</glossterm>, <glossterm>nedovos</glossterm>)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What  is  the significance  of the single  ox and single  ram that we must bring on the day of Shmini Atzeres?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the Parsha end  off with the statement that Moshe spoke to the Jews “I all that he was commanded”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which occasions do we read from this  Parsha (other than on Shabbos)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many separate topics (subjects) can you find in this Parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
