<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayigash</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>“And Yehuda approached him (Y0seif),” etc. Prove that he spoke harshly to Yoseif.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>"Because you’re like Paroh.” What is the meaning of this phrase? (Four ideas.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>According to Yehuda, Yoseif’s first question to the brothers was not fustified. Why? What does this say about Yoseif’s intentions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Because of fear, Yehuda said something which wasn’t true. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In Yehuda’s explanation, why would Yaakov be so upset if Binyomin were absent?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yehuda argue for Binyomin’s return more than the other brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yehuda offered Mmself as a substitute for because he was better. How? (Mention three ways.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why couldn't Yoseif reveal himself to the brothers while the crowd was there?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif reveal his identity to his brothers? What was their reaction?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In What ways did Yoseif attempt to comfort his brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What lesson in hashgocha protis (divine providence) can we derive from his words?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What message did Yoseif send to his father? Which parts are repeated?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“Behold your eyes see (it) and the eyes of my brother Binyominffetc. What did they see?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why were Yoseif and Binyomin crying on each others necks?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>At What point did the brothers start speaking to Yoseif after his reveiation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Paroh feel when he heard Yoseif’s family was coming to live there? And What offer did he give to Yoseif's brothers (via Yoseii)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>TNhich kinds of gifts did Yoseif send to his father?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif gave his brothers a special warning for their behavior on the road. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What sign did Yoseif give to his father that he is Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov respond to the news? Something great occurred to him. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Whom does one owe a greater honor to, a parent or a grandparent? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What comforts and promises did Hashem make to Yaakov about going to Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yaakov do with the riches he got in Lavan's house? Why? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who are Yaakov’s two granddaughters? How many people left Cnaan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why are Yaakov's people called Nefesh, in the singular? And Eisov's?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov sent Yehuda ahead of him to Mitzrayim. What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why didn't Yaakov kiss and embrace Yoseif as Yoseif did to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif prepared his brothers on how to answer Paroh’s question. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which brother did Yoseif pick to introduce to Paroh? Why? '</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What is the dispute between the Midrash and the Gemora about the brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov describe his years of life to Paroh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which biessing did Paroh get from Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What change happened in Mitzrayim because of Yaakov's arrival? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What offers did the peopie give Yoseif in order to get grain?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif did something special with the population of the Egyptian cities. What? For what purpose?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In what connection are the terms and ’four-fifths’ mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How does the above relate to the giving of tzedakah (charity)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the quality of life for Yaakov’s famiiy in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“His soul is bound up with his soul.” About Whom is this written?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In What connection is the number ten mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In Paroh’s message to Yaakov’s family there was a prophecy. What was it?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
