<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Miketz</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>“At the end of two years,” etc. From when are these years counted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The seven fat cows had ‘good iooks.’ What is the symbolism in this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How is Mitzrayim different from other countries in terms of rain?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The seven lean cows ate up the seven fat cows. What is the symbolism here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov and Paroh woke up from their dreams. What did they do afterwards?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What other kinds of interpretations was Paroh offered? His reaction?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>It is said that another royal dreamer was in a worse position than Paroh. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the three damaging facts that the butler mentioned about Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which preparations did Yoseif do prior to his appearance before the king?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yoseif say to Paroh about his ability to interpret dreams?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Name at least two changes in Paroh’s dream as he recounts it to Yoseif.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“What Hashem wants to do He <emphasis role="bold">showed</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">told</emphasis> to Paroh,” etc. Why that change?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did the dream repeat itself to Paroh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif know that the seven good years would come first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the plan that Yoseif proposed to Paroh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the king’s reaction to Yoseif’s pian?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Paroh accorded many honors to Yoseif. Name five.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which of the honors was the main symbol of a transfer of power?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Do you know of another case in history where this symbol of power transfer was used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Everyone in Mitzrayim called Yoseif <glossterm>Avraich</glossterm>. What does this mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How old was Yoseif when he got married? What was his wife’s name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the names of Yoseif’s two sons? Their meanings?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif arrange for the storage of grain in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yoseif ask the people who came for grain to do? Their reaction?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov ‘see’ that there was hope in Mitzmyim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov said to his sons, “Why do you show off?!” Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov hint at a prophecy about the duration of the exile in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“<emphasis role="bold">Yoseif’s ten brothers</emphasis> went down to buy food.” Explain the emphasis.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why wasn’t Binyomin sent along? What rule do we derive from this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did the brothers come in through different entrances?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>One prophecy of Yoseif’s dreams already came true. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“And Yoseif recognized his brothers but they didn’t recognize him.” Why? (Two explanations.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In one of the brothers’ statements, there was a spark of <glossterm>ruach hakodesh</glossterm> (divine inspiration). How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif accused them of being spies. What proof did he offer? Their response?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In what connection did Yoseif mention to them about the destruction of Sh’chem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What proof were the brothers told to provide to prove their honesty?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What conversation did the brothers have when they thought Yoseif didn’t understand?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif react to their conversation? Why? Who was the translator?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yoseif pick Shimon to be imprisoned? (Two reasons.) For how long?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>One of the brothers opened his bag at a stop on the road. Who was it? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why were they all trembling upon discovering the money in their bags?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov suspected his sons of a cruel deed. What? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What offer did Reuven give to Yaakov? Yaakov’s response?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yehuda gave the brothers some advice. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What complaint did Yaakov voice to his sons over their story to Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did the brothers explain their behavior to Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yehuda asked his father to send along Binyomin. By which guarantee?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>As he spoke there was a spark of prophecy in Yehuda’s words. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov agreed to send Binyomin but advised them to bring <emphasis role="bold">gifts</emphasis> along. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of prayer (of a historic nature) did Yaakov say before the sons left?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>There was also a spark of prophecy in his words of prayer. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why were thee brothers scared when they were brought to Yoseif’s home?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did they say to Yoseif’s housekeeper? His answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What special blessing did Yoseif give to Binyomin? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif was moved to tears after his conversation with Binyomin. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why does it say that it is abominable to the Egyptians to eat with Jews?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why were the brothers impressed by their seating arrangement?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the reason for Binyomin’s getting <emphasis role="bold">five</emphasis> portions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was so special about their drinking wine that day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Binyomin is called ‘the little one.’ Was he reaily a little boy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Here we find one of the ten examples of <glossterm>kal vachomer</glossterm> in the Torah. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of punishment were the brothers willing to accept for stealing the cup? What was the housekeeper’s response?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where did he start the search? Why? Where was it found?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did the brothers answer Yoseif as to why they stole the cup?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the exchange of offers betveen Yehuda and Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>This parsha is always read on Chanukah. Can you find any connection between Chanukah and this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>About how many years are covered in this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
