<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayeishev</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>What is the general difference in the descriptions given of Eisov’s and Yaakov’s families?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where else in the Torah is the above kind of difference noticeable?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What parabie (example) is given for the above from a man who lost a pearl?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How is the story of Yoseif a response to Yaakov’s fears of Eisov’s large crowds and armies? Which parable explains this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In which aspects was Yoseif similar to Yaakov? (Give three.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“These are the generations (biography) of Yaakov,” etc. Why is Yoseif mentioned here? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why shouldn’t tzadikim desire to live a life of tranqulity?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why is Yoseif described here as a youngster (<emphasis role="italic">naar</emphasis>)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who were the sons of Bilhah? How did the brothers treat them? And Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yoseif reported three had things about his brothers. Which things? How was he specifically punished for each of these?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which reason is mentioned for the speciai love Yaakov had for Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did his father show his love to Yoseif? How did the brothers react?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“And they couldn’t speak to him in peace.” What compliment is given here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was Yoseif’s first dream and its symbols for the brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The second dream caused his father to yell at him. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What specific question (objection) did Yaakov have about Yoseif’s second dream?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>There are two interpretations about the symbol of the moon in this dream. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov send Yoseif to Sh’chem? Did Yoseif agree to go? This was heroic. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who was the ‘man’ that found Yoseif wandering in the field?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“He sent him from the <emphasis role="bold">depth of Chevron</emphasis>.” But Chevron is located on a hill. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Reuven react to the plans the brothers were making against Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“And we will see what will happen to his dreams,” etc. Who is saying this to whom? (Two answers.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Reuven reaily intend on keeping Yoseif in the pit? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was inside the pit? And what was not in there? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the Arab caravan of camels transporting? What was special about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What idea did Yehuda propose for Yoseif? Did the brothers accept it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many buyers bought Yoseif? Where did he finally arrive?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When Reuven returned to the pit he was shocked. Why? His reaction?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How come Reuven was <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> present at the time Yoseif was sold?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yosef’s brothers do with his special garment, the <emphasis role="italic">kesones pasim</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov react to the tragic news?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What explanation is given by our Sages why Hashem did <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> reveal the secret to Yaakov? Did Yitzchak know about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov absolutely refuse to accept comfort and consolation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Yitzchak cry for the same reason that Yaakov did? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many years did Yaakov mourn? To atone for what?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Prove that learning Torah exempts a person from <emphasis role="bold">kibud av v’em</emphasis> (honoring one’s father and mother).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yaakov saying he might suffer in <emphasis role="italic">Gehinom</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yehuda demoted from his high position among the brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the name of Yehuda’s wife? Of his daughter-in-law?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why didn’t Yehuda want his third son to marry Tamar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yehuda fooled with his gift offer of a goat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yehuda give the verdict of ‘burning’ for Tamar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which important law did our Sages derive from Tamar’s reply to Yehuda?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>There was a voice from Heaven that explained this event. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Yehuda stay married to Tamar afterwards?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the names of the newly born twins? How were they different from Rivkah’s twins?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why is the word <emphasis role="italic">yad</emphasis> (hand) mentioned here four times (in various forms)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why are Yoseif’s problems with Potifar’s wife mentioned here after the story of Tamar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Even Yoseif’s Egyptian boss noticed that Hashem was with Yoseif. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What effect did his success have on Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yoseif’s behavior inappropriate at this time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What punishment did Hashem bring upon Yoseif then?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of a day did the mistress pick on which to force Yoseif to sin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did she do after Yoseif escaped from her?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did her husband punish Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What impression did the head of the prison get of Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Hashem cause the imprisonment of Paroh’s butler and baker just at that point in time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the crimes of these two officers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>According to our Sages, how did the baker recognize that Yoseif’s interpretation of the butler’s dream was correct?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the dreams of file butler and the baker?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif interpret the butler’s dream and what request did he (Yoseif) make?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the obvious difference between their two dreams?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>According to Yoseif, where do true dream interpretations come from?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did the butler remember the favor that Yoseif asked him to do? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What opportunity was there for the butler to bring up Yoseif’s case?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Can you find any similarity between the beginning and the end of this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Can you find the connection befween Yud-Tes Kislev and Chanukah?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
