<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayishlach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of messengers did Yaakov send to Eisov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What messages did they carry to him? (See posuk 6.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How does the word <glossterm>garti</glossterm> (I lived) carry two ideas?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What response did the malochim bring back to Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov was <emphasis role="bold">afraid</emphasis> and he was <emphasis role="bold">anxious</emphasis>. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>With which three defensive methods did Yaakov prepare himself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“I became <emphasis role="bold">small</emphasis> (diminished) by all the kindnesses.” Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of promise did Hashem give about Yaakov’s children?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“Because with my cane I crossed the Yarden.” What is meant by this? (Two meanings.) </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“He took from what came into his hand.” What came into his hand?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the servants (going with the flocks) supposed to say to Eisov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“And his eleven children,” etc. Where was Dina? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What happened to Yaakov when he was left alone?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did that ‘man’ cause any harm to Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did this ‘man’ beg from Yaakov at daybreak?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yaakov demand in return? Did he get it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“Why are you asking for my name,” etc. Why not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who were the ‘men’ over whom Yaakov was victorious?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>By which prohibition did the Jewish people remember this event?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Was Yaakov ever healed from his limping? If yes, how? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In which order did Yaakov arrange the mothers and the children?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov go in front of them? What did he do as he was approaching Eisov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Eisov embrace him? Why are there dots on the word <glossterm>vayishokaihu</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yoseif go ahead of his mother (unlike the other brothers)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Eisov asked, “Who is this camp (group) that I met?” Which one did he mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When Eisov said, “May you have what is yours” (33:9), it made Yaakov very happy. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov mention to Eisov that he saw the face of an angel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What two reasons did Yaakov give to Eisov for accepting the gift?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What difference was there between Eisov and Yaakov’s statements about their possessions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov explain his refusal to waik along with Eisov and his people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Rashi says that Eisov returned home <emphasis role="bold">alone</emphasis>. What happened to his 400 mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How much time did Yaakov spend in the place called Sukkos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov bought a field from the mayor of Sh’chem. For how much?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>From Padan Aram, Yaakov arrived ‘compiete’ in three respects. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yaakov punished with Dina’s tragedy in Sh’chem? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In which ways are the words of Torah compared to a hammer splitting a rock?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What ‘offer’ did the mayor of Sh’chem give to Yaakov’s sons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did the mayor’s son add to his father’s offer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov’s sons refuse the Mayor’s (and son’s) offers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What counteroffer did Yaakov’s sons present to them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When the mayor’s family spoke to their citizens, they changed the terms of the offers somewhat. How? Why? Did the people accept?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yaakov say to Shimon and Levi after they killed the men?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Shimon and Levi feel <emphasis role="bold">secure</emphasis> in doing their ‘job’ in Sh’chem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov urge his people “to cleanse themselves” after Sh’chem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Hashem say to Yaakov before leaving Sh’chem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yaakov do with all the unclean items he received?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did the nations around Sh’chem try to attack Yaakov’s family? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where in this parsha is there a hint to the idea and effectiveness of <glossterm>Chitas</glossterm> (Chumash, Tehillim, Tanya)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who was Devora? Why was she in that place? What happened to her?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Some say that Rivkah passed away at that time. Why isn’t it mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of ‘blessing’ did Hashem give to Yaakov in this place?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When Hashem promised Yaakov that a <emphasis role="bold">nation</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">nations</emphasis> as well as <emphasis role="bold"
                    >kings</emphasis> will come forth from him, whom exactly did He mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What is hinted in the comparison of Yaakov’s children to ‘nations’ (and ‘goyim’)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>On which item does Rashi comment, “I don’t know what it teaches us”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yaakov’s name changed here again? (See 35:10.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Was each of Yaakov’s sons born alone? What was special about Binyomin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the name given by Rochel to her youngest son? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What name did his father give him? Why? Which name remained?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where was Rochel buried? Do we know the place today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>For which important items was Reuven always considered the firstborn?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>From the mentioning of Yitzchak’s passing we can learn that there is no chronological order in the Torah. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who are the three types of people whose sins are forgiven by Hashem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What are the three reasons that Eisov decided to separate from Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What lesson do we learn from the fact that Timnah was married to Elifaz?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The people of Chori lived in Sayir before Eisov, and are called “settlers of His land.” Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many kings did Eisov’s people have before the first Jewish king?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov’s children put up eight kings that counteracted Eisov’s kings. Who?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The people of Midyan fought against Moav. What finally united them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How is Rome mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which part (posuk) in this parsha is connected with Yud-Tes Kislev? How?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
