<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="bereishis" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Bereishis</title>
    <para>These questions for parshas Bereishis (which were found in handwritten form) were discovered while
            <emphasis>The Chumash Questions</emphasis> was in the process of being printed. It is quite clear that they
        are incomplete and, therefore, it is also possible that they are a first draft. Nevertheless, they are a
        valuable addition to the book, and have been included as an insert, in the absence of anything more
        authoritative.</para>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to Rabbi Yitzchok, which way should the Torah have started? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And why did the Torah start with the story of creation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Torah does not teach us the order of creation.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did our sages explain the meaning of Bereishis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which physical elements were definitely created before Heaven and Earth?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the actual creation ‘change’ from the original plan (because the world couldn’t cope
                with it)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is darkness a creation or is it only the absence of light? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was hovering on the water?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the light created?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was a separation made between light and darkness? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say “one day” instead of “the first day”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to Rashi, when were the angels created?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was the sky created on the first day or the second day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the upper waters remain standing in their place?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is “ki tov” not mentioned on the second day but mentioned twice on the third?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is heaven called shamayim? (Three reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If all the seas are really one body of water, why are they called “seas,” in plural, instead
                of “sea,” in the singular?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The earth didn’t produce the trees properly. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was the earth ever punished? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
