<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="chayei-sara" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Chayei Sara</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why is the word <glossterm>shonoh</glossterm> (year) repeated in the first <glossterm>posuk</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Sara have a good life? What about the troubles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Hebron called <glossterm>Kiryas Arba</glossterm> (City of Four)? Is there a city by this name today? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why is Sara’s death mentioned right after the akeidah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When Avrohom says, “I am a newcomer and an old settler,” What does he mean? (See posuk 4.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was the <glossterm>Meoros Hamachpeila</glossterm> called by this name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was special about Efron? Was he a nice person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How does the Torah hint to us about Efron’s character?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Avrohom’s work make a difference in Hashem’s Kingship?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Avrohom ask from Eliezer? Why was it necessary (in your opinion)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Avrohom warn him about? What question did Eliezer ask Avrohom about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why didn’t Avrohom want Yitzchak to marry a girl from the local population (the people of Cnaan)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How were Avrohom’s camels recognizable in the street?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Eliezer had “all his master’s riches <emphasis role="bold">in his hand</emphasis>.” How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of <glossterm>midoh</glossterm> (trait) was the girl supposed to have? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Eliezer recognize that Rivkah was a special person (even before he spoke to her)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In what way did Rivkah offer to give more than she was asked?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was symbolized by the jewelry that Eliezer gave her? (Check the numbers.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did he ask her who she was <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> giving her the gifts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Eliezer do and say after Rivkah invited him to the house?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Lavan run so fast to greet Eliezer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Eliezer have any personal plans for Yitzchak? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Avrohom reject these plans?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How do we know that Eliezer had <glossterm>kfitzas haderech</glossterm> (a miracle to quicken his trip) and why was it necessary (in your
                opinion)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How do we know that the talk and stories of the Avos and their servants are more precious than our Torah learning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many times is Eliezer’s story repeated in the parsha? Do you notice any changes in the recounting?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How do we know that even non-Jews believed that a <glossterm>shidduch</glossterm> (match) is <glossterm>bashert</glossterm>
                (predestined)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How can we tell that Rivkah’s brother was a <glossterm>rasha</glossterm> (sinner)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How do we know that one must thank Hashem for good news?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What happened to Besueil? How do we know?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>From where do we learn that a woman must be asked whether she consents to a marriage and cannot be forced into it by her parents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What ‘daring’ answer did Rivkah give to her family?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was Yitzchak doing when Rivkah arrived?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What were the special miracles and blessings that Sara had in her tent? Did Rivkah have them? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of <emphasis role="bold">special gift</emphasis> did Yitzchak get from his father?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What <emphasis role="bold">strange gift</emphasis> did the other children get?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why is the word <glossterm>shonoh</glossterm> repeated in connection with Avrohom’s passing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How do we know that Yishmael did <glossterm>teshuvah</glossterm> (repented)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Avrohom afraid to bless Yitzchak? What did Hashem do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which mitzvoh did Hashem do after Avrohom’s passing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where is <glossterm>Minchah</glossterm> (afternoon) davening mentioned in this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In this parsha there is a special hint to one of Rebbe’s main <glossterm>mivtzoyim</glossterm>. Where?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
