<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="vayechi" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayechi</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>This parsha is closed-in with the previous one. Give two reasons for this.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many years did Yaakov live in all? in Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What request did Yaakov make to Yoseif? Was an oath involved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Among the three Avos, who lived the longest? The shortest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The kindness that is done to the dead is call ‘true kindness.’ Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov asked not to be buried in Mitzrayim. Thee reasons are given. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where did Yaakov ask to be buried? Why? Why did he bow at the head of the bed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>There is a parable given here about a fox. Who is being compared to a fox?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who told Yoseif about Yaakov’s condition? Who was a regular pupil of Yaakov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov make a special effort to sit up in bed when Yoseif arrived?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Prove that kings should be honored even if they personally are unworthy.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of gift did Yaakov offer to Yoseif? Why did <emphasis role="bold">Yoseif</emphasis> get it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why does Yaakov tell the story of Rochel’s death and burial here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where is Rochel buried? Why? What is so unusual about this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov knew his grandsons very well. Why then did he ask, “Who are they?”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov lose his inspiration to bless Efrayim and Menashe?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif prove the proper status of his sons? What else did Yoseif do to get Yaakov to bless his sons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What did Yaakov say to Yoseif about his feelings on seeing him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov blessed his grandsons twice. What was the first blessing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov liken Efrayim and Menashe to <emphasis role="bold">fish</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yoseif attempt to change the position of Yaakov’s hands?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yaakov explain his refusal to do so?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In which ways was Menashe great in the future? How was Efrayim greater?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the second blessing Yaakov gave the two grandsons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What special portion in Eretz Yisroel did Yoseif get? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What general blessing did Yaakov give Yoseif concerning all the brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Before Yaakov blessed each of his sons he wanted to tell something to all. What? Why did he not say it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In what way was Reuven supposed to be greater than his brothers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>He was punished and lost out. For which sin? Who got those honors?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov said that it was <emphasis role="bold">Shimon and Levi</emphasis> who wanted to kill Yoseif. Prove it.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Where did Shimon and Levi learn these things?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov asked that his name not be mentioned in their gatherings. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why did Yaakov curse <emphasis role="bold">their anger</emphasis>? What future did he predict for them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which praise did Yehuda get in connection with Yoseif’s story?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why was Yehuda referred to as ‘young lion’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was met by the prophecy, “Leadership will <emphasis role="bold">never</emphasis> depart from Yehuda”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>“Until Shiloh will come,” etc. Who is meant here? Why that name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which material blessings were predicted here for Yehuda?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was Zevulun’s business? Where was his territory (in Eretz Yisroel)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What special arrangement did Zevulun have with Yissochor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Rashi and Unkelos (Targum) explain differently the description of Yissochor’s blessing. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What prophecy did Yaakov say about Shimshon of <glossterm>sheivet</glossterm> (the tribe of) Don?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When in our prayers do we recite this posuk that relates to Shimshon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What great blessing did Yaakov express on sheivet Gad? Is that posuk recited too?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which great product is abundantly produced in Asher’s part of the land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which future words are prophetically in Yaakov’s words about Naftali? (Two answers.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How does Yaakov describe the special charm that Yoseif possessed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who were those that embittered Yoseif’s life? Those who disliked him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What special blessings did Yoseif get, similar to those Yaakov received?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Yaakov said that the blessings Hashem gave him are bigger than those given to his father and grandfather. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What are the symbols of ‘morning’ and ‘evening’ in Binyomin’s blessing? (Check Targum Unkelos too.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why does he repeat again in posuk 28, that Yaakov blessed them all?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Who got the longest blessing? The shortest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In connection with whom are these animals mentioned: lion, deer (gazelle), snake, wolf, ox, donkey, horse?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>In describing Yaakov’s passing, it does not mention that he <emphasis role="bold">died</emphasis>. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How come the Egyptians cried for Yaakov for seventy days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Did Eisov have a share in the <glossterm>Meoras Hamachpeila</glossterm>? Did he get it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Paroh said to Yoseif, “Go as your father <emphasis role="bold">made you swear</emphasis>.” Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why couldn’t Paroh ask Yoseif to break his oath (to Yaakov)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What kind of confrontation was about to take place at Yaakov’s funeral?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was the great honor that Yoseif got from the kings of Cnaan, etc.?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which people were forbidden to carry Yaakov’s coffin. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Which two of his sons didn’t carry it? Why? Who took their places?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>On the way <emphasis role="bold">from</emphasis> the funeral the brothers are mentioned before the others. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What caused the brothers to notice a change in Yoseif?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What message did the brothers send to Yoseif? Who were the messengers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did they phrase the message in a way that wasn’t exactly true?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Why <emphasis role="bold">didn’t</emphasis> Yaakov ask Yoseif to forgive and not to avenge his hurt (on his brothers)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How did Yoseif react to their pleading? What did he promise them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>What was Yoseif’s final request from his brothers and their families?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>How many parshiyos are there in <glossterm>sefer</glossterm> (the book of) Bereishis? Which is the longest? The shortest?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
