<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Korach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And Korach took,” etc. What odd he take? (Two sxpianations.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Whose name is not montionezi with Korach’s ancestors? “Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove £hat Korach’s children survived.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">hich firibe helped Korach most? y? What is the saying absut it"?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">ich appointmem 0% leadership angered Korach the most? y?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">I 31 does this parsha feilow the (ending 0% the) previous one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Moshe heard and fell on his face.” Why didn’t he pray?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Some ’kal vachomer’ approaches are wrong. Korach had one. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"The whole csmmunity is My,” etc. What did Kcrach mean by this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What other objection did. Korach have Moshe’s appointments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did MQShe suggest to wait until the morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Masha suggested thai they offer ketores. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Koxach dare undertake such great risks?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe saw something in the future which Korach didn’t. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe first speak softly i0 Korach, then spoke harshly to ail Levi'im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe answer to Korach’s objection about positions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">at message did Msshe send to Dosson and Avirom? Their answers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did oshe try so hard to expiain things to all these people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not turn to their gift (offering).” Which offering? (TWO meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Moshe ever have an opportunity to benefit from the nation? Did. he benefit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Korach incite the people against Moshe that night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe say to Hashem, "One man sins and You, are angry at everybody”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was everybody told to move away from Korach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we grove that machlokes (discord) is punished more severeiy than other sins.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What test Moshe propose to see who is right?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happened to Korach and his people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And What happened to the 250 who brought ketores?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did they do with fire—pans used for the keteres? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the above punishments, Why did a plague come upon them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe know the method for stopping a plague?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By what power (besides ketores) did Aharon stop the plague from spreading?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the special message of using ketores to stop the plague?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose of taking tweive kaves (sticks) from the tribes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon’s stick grow almonds, not other fruit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of ’guarding' were the Kohanim and Levi'im told to do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the parsha of matanos kahuna (gifts) written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of gifts from produce are enumerated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And gifts from animals? HOW about human gifts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which of these gifts is still given today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which gifts are commancied to be given to Levi’im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In What cannection is salt mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is it seen here that this parsha (on gifts) is very beloved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Levi'im give any gifts to Kohanim? Was it hoiy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Levi took his maaser before terurnah was given to the Kohein, what was he suppose to do? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which month did we bless this Shabbos? When is Bosh Chodesh? What’s speciai about this month in Chassidic history?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are the special tefillos for this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are especially happy days that Chassidim celebrate in this month. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are days in this month which will be happy ories as soon as Moshiach comes. Which clays?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
