<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Shelach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is this parsha (about the spies) written next to the previous parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who sent the spies (<glossterm>meraglim</glossterm>), Hashem or Moshe? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Hashem angry about it? Why? What did Hashem do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say “according to Hashem’s consent,” etc. Did Hashem agree?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“They were all (important) men,” etc. But weren’t the spies bad people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the purpose in Moshe changing Yehoshua’s name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the meraglim told to see the Negev (south) first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“See what kind of land it is,” etc. What kinds of lands are there?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How could they recognize whether the nations there were strong?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And... are there any trees?” How does Rashi interpret this question? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who went to the city of Chevron? Why? What was his reward?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why can’t we say that Chevron was built seven years before Tzoan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Then why does it say that <emphasis role="bold">it was built</emphasis> seven years before Tzoan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many people were needed to carry one cluster of grapes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which members of the spy group carried nothing? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were they able to tour <emphasis role="bold">the whole country</emphasis> in 40 days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is an open contradiction between the Rashi for pesukim 3 and 26. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did they mention that <emphasis role="bold">Amalek</emphasis> is near the Jordan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the spies have to say, “It is a land of flowing milk and honey”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What smart device did Kalev use to get their attention?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Kalev express his <emphasis role="bold">absolute confidence</emphasis> in Moshe?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the two main negative factors that the spies mentioned about the land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the spies misinterpret a special kindness of Hashem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the meraglim know that they seemed like ants in the eyes of the natives?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the crying complaint that the people voiced to Moshe and Aharon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the people ready to do after complaining? According to our Sages?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe and Aharon react to the people then? And Kalev and Yehoshua?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the last statements that Yehoshua and Kalev made to the people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the people want to do to these two? What stopped them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was Hashem going to keep His oath to the Avos if He punished the whole nation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What argument did Moshe bring up in defense of the community?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you find a passage in our prayers that uses the same argument? (Try Hallel.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What discussions did Hashem and Moshe have about Hashem’s anger? How was Hashem proven right?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What ‘compromise punishment’ did Hashem give them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times did the people test Hashem in the desert?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It is said that Kalev had two ‘spirits’ (ideas) in his mind. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Hashem mention that the Amalek and Canaanite are in the valley?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that a ‘community’ (<glossterm>minyan</glossterm>) consists of at least ten people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The people were told by Hashem, “What you spoke to Me, will happen to you.” How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were they supposed to be punished during <emphasis role="bold">40 years</emphasis>? Which other sin was remembered and punished now?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Yehoshua and Kalev <emphasis role="bold">lived</emphasis> from those people,” etc. What does this tell us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the people attempt to do against Hashem’s advice? Result?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the subject of wine and oil offerings (<glossterm>nesochim</glossterm>) written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much wine and oil must accompany an offering of a lamb? A ram? A bull?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The obligation to give <glossterm>challa</glossterm> starts at a different time than other gifts. How? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much challa must be given? Who gets it? And today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">One who worships idols, what is he comparable to?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the atonement procedure for the community that mistakenly worshipped idols?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if an <emphasis role="bold">individual</emphasis> did it mistakenly? And if he did it intentionally?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the story of the <glossterm>mekoshesh</glossterm> (wood gatherer) an embarrassment for the community?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Didn’t they know that there is capital punishment for desecration of the Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was the mekoshesh given a proper warning? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was done to him while they were waiting for the answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Hashem’s answer to them? Did they obey?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which part of the garment is called <glossterm>tzitzis</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a <emphasis role="bold">blue thread</emphasis> in the tzitzis (when available)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And you will remember all the mitzvos,” etc. How is this accomplished through tzitzis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who are the ‘spies’ and the ‘agents’ for the body to do sins?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it repeat at the end of the last posuk the words from its beginning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the exodus from Mitzrayim mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why only on a garment of <emphasis role="bold">four corners</emphasis>? Is it related to <emphasis role="bold">four cups</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are these three subjects written next to each other: <glossterm>avodah zorah</glossterm>, Shabbos, and tzitzis? (According to Rabbi Moshe the
                Darshon.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which month is blessed this Shabbos? What are the special days of the month?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If sending spies wasn’t successful the first time, Why did Yehoshua send spies before entering the land?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
