<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Tzav</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to Rabbi Shimon, why does it say here <glossterm>‘tzav’</glossterm> (command) instead of ‘daber’ (speak)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does posuk 2 tell us about the fats and limbs?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If something became posul, does it still burn on the mizbeyach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the avodah of <glossterm>terumas hadeshen</glossterm>? When did the Kohein change garments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where was the fire for the menorah lighting taken from? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were two general kinds of Korban Minchah that the Israelites brought. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the <glossterm>kometz</glossterm> from the above Menachos was taken without <glossterm>kavana</glossterm> (intention), is it OK?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can blemished Kohanim eat from the Menachos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There was a certain korban that regular Kohanim brought during their dedication and the Kohein Gadol brought every day. Which was it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who ate the Korban Minchah that Kohanim brought? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What can we learn about koshering earthenware and metal dishes from that which is written regarding the Korban Chatos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which of these are <glossterm>kedoshim kalim</glossterm> and which are <glossterm>kodshai kedoshim</glossterm>: Chatos, Olah, Asham, Shlomim,
                Minchah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long is the ‘eating time’ for a Korban Shlomim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is eating a Korban punishable by <glossterm>koreis</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for eating <glossterm>cheilev</glossterm> (forbidden fats)? Blood?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which parts of a Korban Shlomim are given to the Kohanim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which commandments does Rashi comment: “There is not (necessarily) a chronological order in the Torah”? Why here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Take Aharon,” etc. How is Moshe supposed to take him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And gather the community at the door of the <glossterm>Ohel Moed</glossterm>.” What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special miracle occurred at this gathering?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does Moshe repeat here: “This is the thing that I was commanded to do”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which activity does Rashi remark, “I don’t know where he was commanded on it.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The mizbeyach was <emphasis role="bold">cleansed</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">sanctified</emphasis>. Why both things?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Besides the shemen hamishcho, what else was put on Aharon and his sons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">One part of a korban was burned on the mizbeyach <emphasis role="bold">only during the <glossterm>miluim</glossterm></emphasis>. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint here about the separation of the Kohein Gadol before Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Aharon and his sons did all the things,” etc. What is the special compliment here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special name given to this Shabbos? Why? Special customs?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
