<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vayikra</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And He called,” etc. Why did Hashem <emphasis role="bold">call</emphasis> Moshe before speaking to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the appearance of Hashem to Moshe different than to Bilam? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who else <emphasis role="bold">calls</emphasis> one another? Why? Where do we mention it in davening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the breaks? Their purpose? Was Moshe <emphasis role="bold">called</emphasis> at these breaks? Why? What do we derive from this about our
                learning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Hashem spoke in <emphasis role="bold">him</emphasis>.” Who is excluded here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was the voice of Hashem high? How far did it reach? Who <emphasis role="bold">didn’t</emphasis> hear it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is <emphasis role="bold">Adam</emphasis> mentioned in connection with the korbanos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are six categories of <glossterm>pesulim</glossterm> in korbanos. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If an <glossterm>Olah</glossterm> gets mixed in with other sheep, what happens?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person promises an Olah then refuses to give it, do we force him? Proof? <emphasis role="bold">How</emphasis> do we force him? (See Rambam, Laws of
                Gerushin 8:2.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If we do force him, how can the korban be ‘according to his will’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kinds of sins does a Korban Olah atone?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a non-Kohein slaughter the korban? Take the blood? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“They should put fire,” etc. But wasn’t there a fire sent from heaven?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">if a Kohein is ‘too well dressed’ or ‘not so well dressed’ his avodah is posul. Explain and give proof.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the requirements for a korban of fowl (pigeons, doves) to be kosher?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the insides (intestines) of fowl thrown out, and not those of sheep?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the doves burned on the mizbeyach with their <emphasis role="bold">wings</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Regarding both sheep and fowl, it says, <emphasis role="italic">‘Reyach nichoach laShem.’</emphasis> What does this teach us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say <emphasis role="italic">‘Venefesh ki sakriv’</emphasis> only in reference to a Korban Minchah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which parts of a Korban Minchah could be done by non-Kohanim? Which part must the Kohein do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The fistful is called a <emphasis role="bold">reminder</emphasis>. For what?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did the Kohein Gadol and regular Kohein get the same portions? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the two opinions concerning the application of oil on a Minchah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of oil is kosher for Menachos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What two items cannot be brought with a Korban Minchah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">All korbanos required <emphasis role="bold">salt</emphasis>.Why is this called <glossterm>bris</glossterm> (covenant)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Most Menachos are voluntary except one. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are certain korbanos called <glossterm>shIomim</glossterm>? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The daily Tamid had to be the first korban of the day. Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kind of sins is a Korban Chatos required?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person writes part of a word on Shabbos, does he bring a Korban Chatos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a Kohein Gadol sins, why is this called the ‘guilt of the nation’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of situation is described in posuk 4:13?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Hashem loves <glossterm>Am Yisroel</glossterm> (the Jewish nation) more than He loves the Kohein Gadol.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of <glossterm>aveiros</glossterm> (sins) are described in pesukim 5:1-3?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kind of Korban do all <emphasis role="bold">those</emphasis> people (in question 36) bring?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When an Olah and Chatos are brought, which goes first? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person was rich when he sinned, and then became poor, which kind of korban is he required to bring? (And if vice versa?) Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of aveiro is described in posuk 5:15?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of Korban Asham is mentioned in posuk 5:18? Its purpose?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kind of aveiros does this Asham atone?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of lessons do Rabbi Akiva, Rabbi Yosai, Rabbi Yosai Haglili, and Rabbi Eliezer learn from here?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
