<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="chanukah" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Chanukah</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which miracles are celebrated on Chanukah? When did they happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the meanings of the name Chanukah? Why eight days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are some of the differences between the celebrations of Chanukah and Purim? Reasons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What activities are forbidden because of Chanukah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the changes in the davening of Chanukah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How important is the mitzvoh of lighting the menorah (in monetary terms)? Why is it unique?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to the Gemora, there are three levels in doing this mitzvoh. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do children light? Do women have to light?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person is not at home, does he have to light?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which oils or candles may be used? Which are preferred?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we need new wicks every night? Which wicks are best?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one use gas or electricity to fulfill the mitzvoh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Must one have a menorah when using candles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can two people light the same menorah at the same time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one use a dish with oil and put several wicks into it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May we derive benefit from the lights? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the ending of the brochos for Shabbos and Chanukah candles differ?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May we one candle from another? What is the <glossterm>shamash</glossterm> for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is it possible that a thousand candles should become unusable for private use because of a Chanukah candle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one use the Chanukah lights for private use after they burned the proper time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May oil or wicks left over after Chanukah be used for personal use?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can the oil that is left over in the menorah be kept for next Chanukah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper time for lighting? The earliest? The latest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which activities are forbidden once the time for lighting arrives?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where was the menorah placed in the time of the Gemora? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where do we place if today? (State various customs.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper height (from the floor) for the menorah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can oil be added while the lights are burning them give it more time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one forgot to say <glossterm>Shehecheyanu</glossterm> on the first night, can he say it the next night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">if one forgot to light all night what should he do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens if a person lit too many or too few candles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one light the menorah while holding it in his hand? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the candle was extinguished before its time, does it have to be refit? Should it be?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person eats in one place and sleeps in another, where should he light?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What about people who eat in a common dining room?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A person who is travelling on a bus, plane, or train during candle lighting time, what should he do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one is a guest at a home, how should he do the mitzvoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we light in shul? Why do we light in the morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When are the Chanukah candles lit 0n Erev Shabbos? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much oil must be put in on Erev Shabbos? And candles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we light on Motzei Shabbos, before or after Havdala? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we read in the Torah on Chanukah? Why? How many aliyos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which Rosh Chodesh do we say the entire Hallel? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What game is played on Chanukah? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one forgets <glossterm>Al Hanissim</glossterm> in davening what should he do? And if it happened in bentching? And if one forgot <glossterm>Haneiros
                    Halalu</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are the meals of Chanukah in the category of ‘seudas mitzvah’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many Torahs do we use on Shabbos Chanukah? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It is said that on Chanukah, Sefardim and Ashkenazim reverse their custom. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
