<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="shavuos" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Shavuos</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the <emphasis role="bold">five names</emphasis> of this Yom Tov and their reasons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there no specific date given in the Torah for this holiday? (How does the Torah describe the date for Shavuos?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Each of the five days prior to Shavuos the Jews did something in preparation for Matan Torah. Can you describe them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the five symbols connected to Matan Torah that are all connected with the number three?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was born on Shavuos? Who passed away on Shavuos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the ‘two loaves,’ and what was done with them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which day (of which month) was the Torah given? (Two opinions.) On which day of the week?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Bikurim are brought from the seven species of fruit. Can you name them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the ‘Torah reading’ for the first day? For the second? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a minhag to stay up the first night of Shavuos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Many communities say <glossterm>Tikun</glossterm> Shavuos night (and some study). Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a minhag to daven Maariv <emphasis role="bold">late</emphasis> on Shavuos night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which Haftaros are read on the two days? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many days is Shavuos celebrated in Eretz Yisroel? In exile? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We do not say <glossterm>Tachanun</glossterm> from Rosh Chodesh until the 12th of Sivan. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we do the morning blessings (and negel vasser) after staying up all night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a custom to decorate the home and the shul with greenery and/or flowers?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the reasons for the minhag of eating <emphasis role="bold">dairy foods</emphasis> on Shavuos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Must we also eat meat on Shavuos? Why? How do we separate between the two?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which special prayer do we say on the second day of Shavuos? (Hint: Most children leave then.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are two ways of reading the Ten Commandments in the Torah? Which one is used? Why? What is <glossterm>akdamus</glossterm>? Our custom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Ten Commandments contain an open hint to the 620 mitzvos. What is it? </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Matan Torah</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="23">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was offered the Torah before we were? What was their response? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Our Sages said that the entire creation was waiting for the Torah and shaking. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who were offered by our nation as guarantors to Hashem for the observance of Torah and were rejected? Accepted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which creatures desired to get the Torah? Why were they rejected?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was the Torah given in the desert? Why on a low mountain?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which secrets from the Heavenly angels did the Jews find out?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why wasn’t the Torah given to us immediately after the Exodus?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When we said ‘<glossterm>Naaseh venishmah</glossterm>’ (we shall do and we shall listen) we were immediately rewarded. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the special miracles in the sights and sounds of Matan Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the Ten Commandments said in the singular (not plural) verb form?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are some of the differences between the Ten Commandments that are written in parshas Yisro and those in parshas Vo’eschanan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the Torah written down, at once or in stages? By whom? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who divided the Torah into pesukim? Into sedras? Into aliyos? Into chapters?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many sedras are there? Pesukim? Words? Letters?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are several types of letters in the Torah. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>The Book of Ruth</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="38">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Megillas Ruth read an Shavuos (in Tikum or in public)? Who wrote it? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was the father of Ruth? Who was her mother-in-law?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Boaz? How were he and Ruth related to King David?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were great acts of kindness in this book. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Orpah? Who was her grandchild? What can we learn from the difference between her and Ruth?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Elimelech? Machlon? Kilyon? From which tribe were they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were the above people punished? Why not Naomi?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kinds of dinim do we derive from Megillas Ruth?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is Ruth related to Avrohom Avinu?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Since Ruth came from Moav, whose people were forbidden to intermarry with Jews, how was she permitted?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
