<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Eikev</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kinds of mitzvos are meant here in the first posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do We know (from Rashi) that it means these kinds of mitzvos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you give some exampies of these kinds of mitzvos? '</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reward is promised for keeping these mitzvos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Name five blessings we will receive as rewards.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"if you’ll say. . .the nations are too many strong for me,” etc. What’s the reply?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Remember the signs, the wonders, the strong hand, the outstretched arm.” Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Lest the animals become too many,” etc. Do we have to fear them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the warnings concerning gold and silver idols?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">According to the Midrash, who gets the credit for a mitzvoh done by two? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What lesson did the Iewish nation learn from the men?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What nisim (miracles) occurred to the people’s ciothing in the desert? To their feet?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which qualities of Eretz Yisroel are mentioned here? What are the seven species?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the mitzvoh of bentching meals stated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What warning is given for those who say, “My power and the strength of my hand produced for me these riches”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reminder is given for those who settle down and. enjoy the good life’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And if the people Wiil start worshipping idols, What will happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Here, too, there is a statement which begins with ’Shma Yisroel.’ What does it say?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don't say, ’Because of my righteousness and their Wickedness.’ Explain:</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many examples does Moshe bring to show our stiff-neckedness?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe do on the mountain in the three periods of forty days.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How were the first and the last forty days similar? Proof? What were the middle ones like?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the dates for each of these forty-day periods?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Hashem want to do to Aharon? Did he do it? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe do with the golden calf? One act is not mehtioned here. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe gave two big reasons why Hashem shouldn't punish us. What were they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe didn’t do things in the exact order in which he was told. How? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">An ark was built for the Luchos. What was it used for later?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the Iews travelied to Masera....1here Aharon died,” etc. Why is this travel mentioned here? Did Aharon really die in Masera? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A certain thing is compared hereto the breaking of the Luchos. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which sin was equal in Hashem’s eyes to the sin of the golden calf?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A. certain battle between the Levi’im and the other tribes is hinted at here. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"At tha€ time Hashem separated the tribe Levi,” etc. Which time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Therefore the tribe Levi got no share in the land,” etc. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">fiove that " everything is in the hands of Heaven except the fear of Heaven"</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"In the place of Hashem's greatness you also find His humility.” Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that food and clothing are considered important gifts.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that “a fault that you have, don’t say it about your friend."</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say that Hashern is “The Master of all Masters”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is meant by saying, "Hashem does not accept a bribe”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that money "keeps a person standing on his feet.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the opinions (and proofs) of Rabbi Yehuda and Rabbi Nechemiah concerning the swallowing up of Korach and his group?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the statement, Chevron was seven times better then Tzoan."</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the qualitative advantages of the iand of Exetz Yisroel over Egypt?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what ways are mountains superior to flat lands?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Hashem is concerned with Eretz Yisroel," etc. Isn't He concerned with aii lands?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"His eyes are always on it (Eretz Yisroel) from the beginning of the year." What is He watching for? When is the beginning of the year?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I am commanding you today,” etc. But weren't they told that before?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“To love Hashem.” Could there be any other motives to do mitzvos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And to serve Him with all your heart,” etc; How may that be done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Certain things are repeated here from the parsha of Ve’ahavta. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">" And 1 shall give your rain in time, yoreh and malkosh. What do these names mean? When is the right time for rain?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the special blessings promised here for the grass (for ammals)? For food (for humans)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Watch yourself lest your hearts stray,” etc. Why may that happen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Ané you will turn away“ .and worship idols.” How does one lead to the other?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What example from a prince is given to explain the idea of exile?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The generation of the Fiood got an extension. Why would we not get one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">‘Nhy does it speak about keeping mifzvos after mentioning the exile?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Then is a'father supposed to start teaching his child? .Proof? And if he does not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint in the Torah about techiyas hameisim? fl</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You must carefully watch the mitzvoh,” etc. (11/22) What special care is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“To walk in His ways.” Which ways? "And to cleave ’to Him.” How is that possible?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is special about the 20th of Av?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
