<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Re'eh</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Look, I give before you,” etc. 15 this written in the plural or in the singular?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you find a connection (according to thé first posuk) between this parsha and. the month of E1111?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How are the two mountains, Grizim and Evol, connected with the first posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is the description of the activities at these mountains? (Try Ki Save.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From the conditions upon which the blessing and the curse depend, couid it be proven that Hashem rewards even the good thoughts and
                decisions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that one who worships idois, it’s as if he abandoned the Torah entirely.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At Mount Grizim and Evol, what was said first, the curses or the blessings? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is a current city in Eretz Yisroei (besides Jerusalem) mentioned here? (by a different name)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When the people crossed the Yarden, what gave them the security for conquest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is (are) the first big action(s) the Iews must do after conquering the Land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person uproots idols, how is he supposed to do it? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Not just the idols must be destroyed, but also the mizbeyach, matzeivo, the ashairo, and even the names of the idols. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t do such (things) to Hashem.” What is being prohibited here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What question did Rabbi Yishmael ask here? His answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When were they permitted to bring sacrifices on private altars (bamah)? What kind of korbanos did they bring at the bamah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of places were Shiioh, Nov, Given?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Eiiyahu Hanavi brought a korban at Meant Karmei. Was it allowed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The area where the Beis Hamikdash was built belonged to one tribe and to all. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of cattle could be used for private consumption, but could not be used for milking or wool shearing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which (healthy) animals are kosher to eat but cannot be brought as a korban?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"But the blood do not eat,” etc. Why does it have to be mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Spill it on the ground like water,” Which laws about blood are stated. here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In Yehoshua’s time, the Iews weren't able to conquer ]erus_alem (fully). Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the three possible ways to benefit a Levi?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there an obligation for special treatment for a Levi outside of Eretz Yisroei? Proof? Can you think of a reason for this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Torah is opposed to straining one’s budget in order to eat meat.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that during the time of Moshe Rabeinu, the laws of kosher slaughtering were already known. How do we know these iaws today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Rabbi Yehuda and Rabbi Shimon differ about the urgent prohibition against @ating blood. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we learn about the reward for keeping difficult prohibitions (and easy ones)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Guard and listen,” etc. What is there to guard before listening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What strange sight of idol worshipping did Rabbi Akiva see?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give three examples for the prohibition against adding to mitzvos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Compare the prohibition here (13/ 1) to one in pal-shes Vo’eschanan (4/ 2). (See Rashi’s comments and look out for differences.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How can we expiain the fact that a false prophet could perform miracies?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does this prophet want people to do? What is done to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If it already mentioned the keeping of mitzvos, What is added by "listening to His voice?” What is meant by “and to cieave to Him”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it especially embarrassing for a law to abandon tradition?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"From the idols of the nations, which are close to you or far from you," etc. Why mention both?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the six specific prohibitions against favorable treatment of a missionary?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a city turn into an ir hanidachas (a deviant city)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is that kind of city punished? And its wealth?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which city can never become an ir hanidachas? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it preface "You are children to Hashem” to the prohibition against making skin cuts and tearing out hair to mourn the dead?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We are said here to have two kinds of kedusha (sanctity). What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the genera} caution of "Don’t eat anything abominable” include (14/3)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are more numerous, the clean or the unclean animals? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">W’hat are the two general signs of kosher animals (for large animals)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which cattle product does not require kosher slaughtering in order to be eaten?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In parshas Shemini, the kosher and non-kosher animals are enumerated. Why are they repeated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And don’t touch their carcasses.” Prove that this applies "during Yom Tov only.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which bird has three names? Why are all of the names listed? ‘Nhich name has a reason to it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are more numerous, kosher or non-kosher birds? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are there any signs to recognize kosher birds? Kosher fish?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Give it to the convert in your city,” etc. May a convert eat non-kosher?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When you are amongst people who restrict themsekves from something permissible, how are you to act in their midst? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The prohibition against miking meat and milk is mentioned three times. Why? (Compare Rashi’s comments here to his comments in Shemos 34/
                26.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the prohibition against cooking the goat in its mother’s milk mentioned near the mitzvoh of maaser?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">‘Nhat is the rule about eating maaser sheinz' (Where, how, etc)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain: Ieket, shikcha, pe’ah, hefker.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are all the above exempt from the obligation of maaser?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At the end of each three years, a person must clean out his maaser. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On the seventh year (Shmittah) some loans are cancelled. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are two opposing pesukim concerning the existence of poverty in the future. Explain the contradiction and the answer to it.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are two prohibitions here concerning charity What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If we are not required to give charity to make the poor person rich, Why is it that sometimes we must provide him with horses and servants? How
                about a shidduch?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a mitzvoh to complain to Hashem against someone who refuses to be kind to you? Does the complaining make a. difference?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times must you give charity to the same person (if asked again)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the order of preference given here for giving out tzedakah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If you know that someone reaily needs help but refuses charity, What should you do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What item cannot be given as a farewell gift (ha’anakah) to a freed servant? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">reason is given to us for the above mitzvoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What uses are prohibited for a firstborn (bechor) kosher animal?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the bechor develops a blemish, What can be done with him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we make sure that Pesach falls in the spring, not the Winter?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did the }ews leave Mitzrayim by night or by day? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which korban is added to the Korban Pesach? Fer What purpose?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is matzo called iechem oni (bread of poverty)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are three time-periods in connection with Korban Pesach. ‘Nhat are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is this part of the parsha read besides this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are two contradictory pesukim about eating matzo‘ How is it resolved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the seventh day of Pesach called Atzeres? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On Yom Tov, Hashem tells us to take care of ’His £0111” and He will take care of 'our fouf.’ How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do "we derive from here concerning the s’chach covering for the Sukkah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times a year do we have to come to the Beis Hamikdash. When?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para dir="ltr">Special</para>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">'Why is the month of E1111 considered special?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do We blow the shofar during this month?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we add in the davening during E1111?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What items shouid be checked in this month?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper Wish to be expressed in this month?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which day is a holiday in this month?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
