<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Vo'eschanan</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Tzadikim could make a request in two ways. Which is the right one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“At thar time,” etc. What was that appropriate time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">This is one of three places where Moshe insisted. On What? Another place?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You started showing your servant,” etc. What did He show? When? When? (Two answers.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">”And Your strong Hand,” etc. Which Hand? What strength is méant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Besides seeing that ’good ianci,’ in general, which specific things did he crave to see? Why was Moshe told ’enough for you.’ in response to his
                request?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was any part of Moshe’s request fulfilled? Which? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And command Yehoshua, and stxengthen him,” etc. Command to do What? And why did he need special strengthening? How was Moshe to strengthen
                him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the problem in the battle of Bi a result of Yehoshua's failure?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And we sat in the valley across from Beis Peor,” “And how Israei observe the laws,” etc. What is the connection?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give examples £01" the prohibition, “Don’t add nor subtract from the mitzvos.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When the nations of the world will hear about our laws, What will they say about us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Watch yourself, lest you forget” etc. What may happen as a result?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“What are the warnings about images? About the sun and the moon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We were exiled two years prior to a certain time. Which time? Was it a favor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How are the events of Tisha B’Av predicted here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is considered ’like worshiping idols’ even though it isn't? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Ask, please, about the early days," etc. (M32) What should we learn from history?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How tail was Adam?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Was there ever such a great thing”? Which thing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the examples given for these deeds: masos, osos, mofsim, milchamah? (See posuk 4/34.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You. have been Shawn to know that there is nothing besides G-d.” How was</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In whose merit did we receive so many great favors? (Exodus from Egypt, Torah, Eretz Yisroei)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Then Moshe separated three cities‘” When did these cities seyarate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe want to separate them now? What is the lesson here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Do not have other gods before me.” When? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Try to notice and mark down the differences between the first and second giving of the Ten Commandments. Example: the reasons for keeping
                Shabbos.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which one of Rashi's comments on the Ten Commandments has been incorporated into the davening of Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvos were given to them before Matan Torah? Give two examples.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 5/19 it says "velo yosof." What are the two meanings here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the Iews heard the divine voice from Har Sinai, they got fearful. Why? What did they request from Moshe? What did Hashem say about
                it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Hashem express in connection with this request?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Moshe happy about the request? Why? The proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does Rashi explain the great statement of "Shma Yisroel” (in posuk 1)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And you shall love Hashem,” etc. Why is it preferable t0 serve out of love rather than fear?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“With all your heart,” etc. What is this referring to? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is meant by “all your soul"? "All your might”? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a. person get to love Hashem (according to the context here)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word veshinantam used. here for the study and teaching of Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the relationship between a rebbi (teacher) and talmid (studefit) described here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And you shall speak (in) them,” etc. What does this add after saying it in the earlier posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"When you go to sleep and when you wake up.” What mitzvoh is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the word totafos mean tefillin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that we aren't obligated to put mezuzos on both doorposts.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of gates require mezuzos? Proof? 7</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should the ]ews expect to find when entering the Holy Land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there an immediate warning following the above gondies?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was this kind of warning mentioned elsewhere in this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When may a man swear in Hashem‘s name? Why only _then?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And you shali do the righteous and the good,” etc. (6/18) What is asked of us here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Have our ancestors ever attempted to test Hashem? If yes, when? Why mention it here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“If your son shall ask you,” etc. Which son (of the ’four sons”) is written about here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What answer is given here? Is it the same as in the Haggadah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give three prohibitions about idol worship mentioned in the beginning of Chapter 7.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Hard question: Prove that a son 0f a Iewish mother and a non-Jewish father is considered Iewish, but not a son of a non-Eewish mother and Iewish
                father.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the differences: mizbeyach, matzez'vo, ashairo, pesilim. (See posuk 7/6.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Not because of your greatness (in population),” etc. What different traits of Iews and non-Jews are described here (according to the Midrash)?
                Exampies?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two categories of tzadikim are mentioned in posuk 7/ 9?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is His reward different for the above two kinds? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">His enemies also get rewarded. Why? Is it good for them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Twice in the parsha is the word hayom (today) emphasized (“That I command you today”). What are the two messages here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special name and mood for this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special day occurs right in the middle of Av (its name, history and observance)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
