<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="acharei" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Acharei</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What mashal does Rashi quote from Rabbi Elazar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is difficult in this posuk that made this mashal necessary?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Because in the cloud,” etc. (posuk 2). Which cloud is meant here? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“With <emphasis role="bold">this</emphasis> Aharon may come in,” etc. With what? When may he come?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which garments <emphasis role="bold">can’t</emphasis> Aharon wear when he goes into the holiest place? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And which garments does he wear? Do we do anything similar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times did Aharon use the <glossterm>mikvah</glossterm> on Yom Kippur? At which points?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What else did Aharon have to do at these intervals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who owned the Kohein Gadol’s Yom Kippur garments? Who owned Aharon’s korban?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the lots drawn for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"><emphasis role="bold">Twice</emphasis> it’s stated, “He should atone for his household.” Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was done with the goat intended for Azazeil?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was special about the ketores used on Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of sins are atoned for the Kohanim and the nation through the Korban Chatos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that His Presence is with us even when we’re tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the <emphasis role="bold">order</emphasis> (sequence) of the Kohein Gadol’s avodah on Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with his garments after Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Not all the Kohanim Gedolim were anointed. Which were not? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is first in line to succeed the Kohein Gadol?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Aharon specially praised that ‘he did as he was told’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one offers a korban outside of the Beis Hamikdash he is compared to a murderer. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes those who offered their korbanos outside had wrong intentions. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the prohibition against <glossterm>sh’chutei chutz</glossterm> (outside offerings) repeated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for eating blood? What do we do to meat to get rid of the blood?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is an animal sacrifice able to atone for a human being?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">To which animals does the mitzvoh of covering the blood apply?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person became tomei by eating from a dead animal, does he get punished?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which sin that occurred in the time of Ezra (circa Second Temple) is hinted at here? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t do like the activities of the Egyptians and Cnaanites.” Why are <emphasis role="bold">these two</emphasis> mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is then meant by the addition, “and don’t follow their laws” (18:3)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And he shall <emphasis role="bold">live</emphasis> by them” (18:5). Which life is meant here? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which family member was not explicitly mentioned in the prohibitions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of sister is not specifically forbidden in the Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can an uncle marry a niece? Can an aunt marry a nephew?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When can one marry a sister-in-law?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one marry two sisters? How could Yaakov marry Rochel and Leah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the land of Israel do to a sinful nation? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When are portions of this parsha read besides on the Shabbos of this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
