<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="bechukosai" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Bechukosai</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What proof is there that the first posuk here refers to toiling in Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the above connected to the next phrase, “You shall keep My mitzvos”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The rain comes in the right (convenient) time if it comes... <emphasis role="bold">when</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What <emphasis role="bold">special blessing</emphasis> is given about certain trees? About eating bread?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which blessing equals the goodness of all other blessings combined?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And a sword will not cross your land,” etc. Isn’t this a repetition of the peace blessing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The enemy will “fall by the sword,” in a special, miraculous way. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Five will pursue 100, and 100 will chase 10,000.” What is the difficulty in this posuk? And the answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And i shall turn to you,” etc. What kind of reward is promised here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of <emphasis role="bold">family</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">personal</emphasis> (physical) blessings are mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And I will establish my covenant with you.” Didn’t we already have one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the Torah describe the <emphasis role="bold">large harvests</emphasis> that will come as a reward?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Name two <emphasis role="bold">spiritual</emphasis> blessings mentioned here.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does Hashem mention <emphasis role="bold">here</emphasis> the fact that He took us out from Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are seven aveiros which follow one another. Which are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do the punishments come in sets of seven? (See posuk 18.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Lack of rain is a punishment. How is the one here worse than the one Moshe said in the punishments of Ki Savo?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of bad attitudes are described in posuk 21?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a specific punishment about baking bread. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 32 there is a punishment that is also a comfort. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which sin is atoned for by the punishment of the land being desolate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many years after the exiling of the ten tribes did the total destruction come? Which were the last two tribes to be exiled? Where did they
                go?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give the count which explains the reason for the 70 years of <glossterm>Galus Bavel</glossterm> (Babylonian Exile).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that the Torah holds each Jew responsible for his friend’s sins?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 37 there is a comforting promise made to the exiled Jews. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of a ‘letter’ exchange is there between Yaakov and Eliyahu? What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“My covenant with Yaakov,” etc. Why are the names of the Avos mentioned in reverse order?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word ‘remembrance’ <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> mentioned in connection with Yitzchak’s name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the <emphasis role="bold">Torahs</emphasis> which He gave,” etc. Why is it written in plural form?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the value of a person estimated for purposes of tzedakah (<glossterm>hekdesh</glossterm>)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which difficult word does Rashi say, “I don’t know where it comes from”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that old age affects a man more negatively than it does a woman?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the saying brought from the Gemora, describing the above conditions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done when a contributor cannot afford to pay the full value?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a person donate just the foot of an animal to the Beis Hamikdash? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that we may not exchange one animal (donated for a korban) for another, even one of equal value?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a donated animal that became blemished be redeemed? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we estimate the value of a field for redemption purposes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of donated (hekdesh) <emphasis role="bold">field</emphasis> returns to the owner in Yovel? Which doesn’t?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of kosher and healthy animal cannot be donated to hekdesh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person donates a tomei (non-kosher) animal to hekdesh, what is done with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person donates his possessions without specifying to whom it is given, who gets them? (Two opinions.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes donating the value of a human to hekdesh is ineffective. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of <glossterm>maaser</glossterm> must be eaten in Jerusalem? How is it stated in the posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What difference is there whether one redeems <emphasis role="bold">his own</emphasis> maaser or <emphasis role="bold">someone else’s</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of maaser is designated by using a whip? What is done with this maaser?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the tenth animal has a blemish, what is done with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint in these pesukim about Yud Shevat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who gets the of aliyah of the <glossterm>tochecha</glossterm> (curses, punishments)? Is he called up?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we say ‘Chazak’ at the end of every Chumash?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
