<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="behar" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Behar</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">All the Mitzvos were given at Sinai. Why then is Sinai mentioned specifically in relation to Shmittah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which types of agriculture (work) are forbidden during years of Shmittah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a mitzvoh of counting (<glossterm>sefira</glossterm>) mentioned here. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the year of <glossterm>Yovel</glossterm> announced? And sanctified? In which month does it begin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to fields and servants during Yovel? Are all servants alike?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we blow the shofar anywhere on Rosh Hashonoh that comes on Shabbos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many Shmittah years are there between two Yovel years?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the prohibition against unfair pricing written near the Yovel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a mitzvoh to do business with a Jew? Proof? Even if it’s overpriced?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"><emphasis role="bold">Twice</emphasis> it is mentioned not to be unfair to another person. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the official punishment for violating the mitzvoh of Shmittah? The reward?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“If you shall say, ‘What will we eat on the seventh year?’” What are they asking here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What promise does the Torah give them? Sometimes the promise is bigger. When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which reason is given to comfort the people for having to return the field to the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that a man should not sell his field except in poverty.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do houses also return to the original owner during the year of Yovel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a field that was sold is redeemed by a friend, how is it done? And by the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one redeem <emphasis role="bold">part</emphasis> of a field? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long after it was sold may a field be redeemed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A house <emphasis role="bold">within a walled city</emphasis> cannot always be redeemed. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the status (for redemption purposes) of a <emphasis role="bold">house in an open city</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many cities belonged to the Levi’im? Were all their cities walled?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are their rights to redeem fields and houses different than others’? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Levi donated his field to the Beis Hamikdash treasury, can he redeem it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When no one redeems the Levi’s field, what happens at Yovel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is the best time to give a person a hand (tzedakah)? What is the example from a load on a donkey?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say “and you shall Fear Hashem,” regarding the prohibition against taking interest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the fact of redemption from Egypt mentioned in connection with interest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason is mentioned here for giving us the land of Eretz Yisroel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the Torah compare <emphasis role="bold">living</emphasis> in Eretz Yisroel to <emphasis role="bold">leaving</emphasis> the land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What must we avoid in the employment of a Jewish servant?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is prohibited when <emphasis role="bold">selling</emphasis> a Jewish servant?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason does the Torah give for the above prohibitions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Then how can Jews in Eretz Yisroel get servants for heavy work?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a Jew employ a Canaanite person? Why? A son of a Canaanite?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 47 the Torah describes a rich person and a poor one. Why are they so?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kind of a Jewish servant is it a mitzvoh to redeem? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason is given for the fact that a servant is freed in Yovel?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a prohibition against idolatry at the end of this parsha? (How is it connected here?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Rashi tells us that the subjects here are arranged in a sequence. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of activity is permitted only in the Beis Hamikdash?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
