<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="emor" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Emor</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the instruction ‘say,’ ‘and you shall say,’ repeat itself here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we derive from the repetition of ‘the Kohanim,’ ‘the sons of Aharon’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May women, or blemished or violated Kohanim become tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who are the seven relatives to whom a Kohein may become tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which case may a Kohein not become tomei to his sister?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is added here in the prohibition of creating a bald spot for the dead?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What new fact is stated here about the prohibition of shaving?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of woman may a Kohein <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> marry?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You shall sanctify him.” How is this done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special treatment we give to Kohanim due to their holiness?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is the punishment different for a daughter of a Kohein who commits adultery?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">in what instance may a Kohein Gadol become tomei to a dead person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can any Kohein do his services in the Beis Hamikdash on the day his parents died?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May a regular Kohein marry a widow? A divorcee? May a Kohein Gadol marry these?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give six examples of physical defects (blemishes) that disqualify a Kohein.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that other blemishes (besides the listed ones) also disqualify a Kohanim.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If and when the defect heals, does the Kohein become kosher for avodah? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Kohanim who have defects, can they eat terumah? Korbanos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When may a Kohein who becomes tomei eat from the above-mentioned things?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove your answer to question 19 from a Mishna text.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May the Kohein’s family members eat terumah? His workers? His cattle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May a Kohein’s daughter who is married to a Levi eat terumah? When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a non-Kohein eats terumah, beshogeig or bemeizid, what happens to him? Can he atone for it in some way?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the difference between a <glossterm>neder</glossterm> and a <glossterm>nedava</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of korban may be accepted even with blemishes? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give five examples of blemishes that disqualify korbanos.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a non-Jew brings a korban, is it accepted? With a blemish?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two animals cannot be slaughtered on the same day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What must one think while slaughtering a korban?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And I will be sanctified,” etc. (22:32) What mitzvoh do we get here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the incorrect way of attempting martyrdom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What proof does Rashi bring from the three greats, Chananya, Michoel, and Azarya?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What would be a good reason to make a leap year?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Shabbos mentioned among the other holidays?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the word <glossterm>Pesach</glossterm> mean in the Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of work is permitted on Chol Hamoed but not on Yom Tov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the Kohein have to wave the Omer (up and down, etc.)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“In all your settlements” (23:14). What are the differing opinions among the Sages concerning the interpretation of this phrase?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it best to count Sefirah at the start of night not later?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of an offering was the Omer? Why its name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special korban is brought on Shavuos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which Yom Tov is not mentioned by name (or title)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the gifts of the poor mentioned in the midst of Yomim Tovim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Does Yom Kippur atone for those who don’t repent? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we sanctify Yom Kippur? And the other Yomim Tovim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the name <glossterm>Atzeres</glossterm> given to the last day of Sukkos? The example for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the <glossterm>esrog</glossterm> called <glossterm>pri eitz hadar</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was the western light of the menorah called ‘testimony’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who ate the Iechem hapanim? What part was burnt on the altar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that through modesty a person is saved from indecent behavior.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
