<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="kedoshim" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Kedoshim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that this parsha was said at the gathering of the nations? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You shall be <emphasis role="bold">holy</emphasis>,” etc. What kind of holiness is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it say, “Each <emphasis role="bold">man</emphasis> should fear his mother and father”? Isn’t a woman also obligated to fear and honor parents?
                Why is <emphasis role="bold">mother</emphasis> mentioned here first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one give <glossterm>kavod</glossterm> (honor) to parents? And how is <glossterm>yirah</glossterm> (fear, respect) expressed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the commandment to observe Shabbos written next to honoring parents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which laws concerning korbanos do we derive from pesukim 5-8?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which gifts to the poor are mentioned in pesukim 9-10?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You shall not steal,” etc. How does this prohibition differ from the one in the Ten Commandments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is a logical connection between the prohibitions in pesukim 11-12?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the warning given concerning the wages of a worker?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not curse the deaf.” Are we allowed to curse others?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t put an obstacle in front of a blind person.” What kind of obstacle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kinds of prohibitions does the Torah commonly add, “and you shall fear Hashem”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of warnings are judges given in posuk 15?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvos and warnings are given about rebuking a friend?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the difference between the sins of <glossterm>lashon horah</glossterm> and <glossterm>rechilus</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What else is forbidden along with the prohibition against revenge?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a prohibition here against being <emphasis role="bold">passive</emphasis>. In which situation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which three types of mixtures (<glossterm>shatnez</glossterm>) are prohibited here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the three phases concerning the fruits of a newly planted tree?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of magic are prohibited in posuk 72 (Ch. 20 and 19:27)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many transgressions are committed when <emphasis role="bold">shaving</emphasis> with a razor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the prohibitions concerning a person’s <emphasis role="bold">skin</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one show respect to an old person? To a scholar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What warnings are given here concerning weights and measures?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for cursing parents? For adultery? For a homosexual act?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the <emphasis role="bold">animal</emphasis> killed when a human commits a sin with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What moral lesson do we derive from it, according to Rashi?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And separated you from the nations to be Mine.” What lesson of conduct does Rabbi Elazar ben Azarya derive from this?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
