<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="metzorah" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Metzorah</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can the metzorah be cleansed at night? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The metzorah is put outside of the camp (or city). How does the Kohein see him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you bring an example from the mivtzoyim which is similar to the above?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the metzorah bring <emphasis role="bold">birds</emphasis> for his cleansing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The species of the birds is not mentioned. Which birds are not acceptable?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the metzorah bring the <glossterm>etz erez</glossterm>, <glossterm>shei</glossterm>, <glossterm>tolaas</glossterm>,
                <glossterm>ezov</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with the <emphasis role="bold">two birds</emphasis> (with the items from the previous question)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the metzorah do on the <emphasis role="bold">first</emphasis> day of his cleanliness? On the <emphasis role="bold">eighth</emphasis>
                day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which parts of the metzorah’s body do they put the <emphasis role="bold">blood</emphasis>? The <emphasis role="bold">oil</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From the ‘13 midos’ of Rabbi Yishmael (in Shacharis) we use three in this parsha. Which midos are used? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Rashi says he doesn’t know why a certain thing is called by its name. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A metzorah who is poor, how are his korbanos different?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it <emphasis role="bold">good news</emphasis> that some homes in Eretz Yisroel have negayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the Torah command to empty the house <emphasis role="bold">before</emphasis> the Kohein comes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done to the house when the negah is first seen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to the person who <emphasis role="bold">eats in</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">sleeps in</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">just
                    enters</emphasis> the closed house? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the negah grows bigger on the seventh day, what is done to the house?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done for the house after the ‘new stones’ remain clean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">An item which a <glossterm>zav</glossterm> touches, sits on, or sleeps on, what tumah does it get?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When does a zav become tahor? What does he have to bring?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of tumah does a lady <glossterm>zavah</glossterm> cause?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of taharah is <emphasis role="bold">common</emphasis> in (almost) all cases?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
