<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="shemini" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Shemini</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And it was on the <emphasis role="bold">eighth day</emphasis>,” etc. Which day of the month was it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was happening during the seven previous days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“That day took ten crowns,” etc. What kind of crowns?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe called the elders of Israel. What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon have to offer a calf for a Korban?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe have to urge Aharon, “Come to the mizbeyach!”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the korbanos were offered, what kind of blessing did Aharon give?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After that blessing Moshe and Aharon went into the ‘holy tent’ again. What for? (Two reasons.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the people react after they saw the Heavenly fire come down?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the blessing that Moshe and Aharon gave to the people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the people feel <emphasis role="bold">embarrassed</emphasis> as long as the <glossterm>Shechina</glossterm> (Divine Presence) didn’t
                come?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the ‘wrong service’ of Nadav and Avihu described in the posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the opinions of Rabbi Eliezer and Rabbi Yishmael about the wrongdoing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Hashem’s name was going to be sanctified in public on this great day. What did Moshe expect?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe find out about his greatness (and Aharon’s) after the tragedy?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Aharon react to his sons’ death? How was he rewarded?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does Hashem’s name become sanctified through the punishment of tzadikim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who were these people: Mishael, Eltzafan, Uziel? What were the first two asked to do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The usual observances of mourners were prohibited to the survivors. What are they? Are these observances kept today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the suffering of a Torah scholar must be shared by all.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that when a Kohein drinks wine, his avodah becomes posul.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who else was prohibited from drinking wine? What if he did? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that Aharon’s other two sons might have died too? What saved them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which korban was burnt? Why was Moshe upset about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the reasons for burning this korban? What reason did Moshe suggest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">To whom was Moshe complaining about the burning? Who answered him? Why him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe liked the answer he was given. What was that answer? What were Moshe’s comments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How were Aharon’s sons Elazar and Issamar rewarded for accepting the tragedy properly?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Hashem put restrictions on the Jewish nation but not on other nations?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe explain to the people about the kosher and non kosher animals? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the two traits that identify the kosher animals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is a kal v’chomer used to determine the status of certain animals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the Torah teach us about the obligation of cleansing ourselves before Yom Tov?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the signs of kosher fish? Kosher birds?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are people allowed to feed non kosher meat to small children? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Carrying a sheretz (rodent) is worse than just touching it. How? (Difference between <glossterm>tumas magah</glossterm> and <glossterm>tumas
                    masah</glossterm>.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A person who has a sheretz for a pet, is he <glossterm>tomei</glossterm> (impure)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A wooden dish that became tomei, how is it purified? And earthen vessels?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove following:</para>
            <orderedlist numeration="upperalpha">
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Food (grain, etc.) cannot become tomei unless it first becomes wet.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">In addition to water, food can be made tomei by wine, oil, etc.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">A <glossterm>vlad hatumah</glossterm> (second level tumah) cannot bring tumah to keilim, only to food.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Water causes food to absorb tumah only if it got wet after it was detached from the ground.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does it mention <emphasis role="bold">here</emphasis> that Hashem took us out from Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special parsha is read this Shabbos? Why at this time?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
