<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="tazria" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Tazria</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the laws affecting humans written after the laws of animals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long is a woman tomei after the birth of a son? A daughter?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is her impure period stated as ‘in <emphasis role="bold">clear</emphasis> blood’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of korbanos does a woman have to bring when she is cleansed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which one of her korbanos actually causes her to become <glossterm>tahor</glossterm> (pure)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can any rabbi decide whether <glossterm>negayim</glossterm> are tomei or tahor? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many hairs have to change to white in order to make the person tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which statement does Rashi comment, “I don’t know its meaning”? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which case is the person declared tomei immediately? When is he locked up?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is a person locked up for a <emphasis role="bold">second time</emphasis>? For how long?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes the person is declared tahor yet must wash (<glossterm>towel</glossterm>) himself and his clothes. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After being locked up what has to happen to his <glossterm>negah</glossterm> to make him tomei? Tahor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the general difference between these: <glossterm>s’ais</glossterm>, <glossterm>sapachas</glossterm>, <glossterm>baheres</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May a Kohein decide on a person with a negah by <emphasis role="bold">getting information</emphasis> about its condition? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is it possible that a person could become tahor even while he has a regular <glossterm>tzoraas</glossterm>? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are certain days and certain people that a Kohein should refuse to check. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the signs of tumah for a negah on the skin? On the head?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Kohein mistakenly declares a person ‘tahor’ who is really tomei, is it OK?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these: <glossterm>nesek</glossterm>, <glossterm>bohak</glossterm>, <glossterm>tzareves</glossterm>, <glossterm>keireiach</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>giveiach</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is a metzorah supposed to do to his clothes? To his hair? What does he announce?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of clothes (materials) can develop negayim? What colors are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with a garment that became tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is the negah supposed to be washed? If the negah’s coloring remains the same what is done to it? And if the negah darkened somewhat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If after washing it, it reappears again what is done to the <glossterm>beged</glossterm> (garment)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the negah was removed after washing it, what is done to the beged?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are there negayim today? Why? How is this connected to the <glossterm>Golus</glossterm> (Exile)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
