<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Bechukosai</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the above connected to the next phrase, “You shall keep My lmitzvus”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The rain comes in the right (convenient) time if it comesmwhan?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">at special biessig is given about ceriain trees? About eating bread?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">ich blessing equals the goodness of all other blessings combined?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And a sword will not cross your land,” etc. Isn’t this a repetition of the peace Messing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The enemy will "fall by the sword,” in a special, miraculous way. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Five will pursue 100, and 109 will chase 10,090.” What is the difficulty in this And the answer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And i shall turn to you,” etc. What kind of reward is promised here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of faily and personal (physical) blessings are mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And I will establish my covenant with you.” Didn't we ah‘eady have (me?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the Torah describe the large harvests that will come as a reward?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Name tWo spirial. blessings mentioned here.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does Hashem mention he“: the fact that He took us out from Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are seven aveiros which follow one another. Which are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do the punishments csme in sets of seven? (See posuk 18.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Lack of rain is a punishment. How is the one here worse than the one Moshe said in the punishments of Ki Save?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of bad attitudes are described in posuk 21?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a specific punishment about baking bread. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 32 there is a punishment that is also a comfort. Expiain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which sin is atoned for by the punishment of the land being desalate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many years after the exiling of the ten tribes did the total destruction come?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which were the last two tribes to be exiied? Where did they go?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give the count which explains the reason for the 70 years of Galus Bavel (Babylonian Exile).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that the Torah holds each Iew responsible for his friends sins?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 37 there is a comforting promise made to the exiled Iews. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of a ’letter’ exchange is there between Yaakov and Eliyahu? What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">”My covenant with Yaakov,” etc. Why are the names of the Aves mentioned in reverse order?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word ’remembrance’ not mentioned in connection with Yitzchak’s name?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And the Tombs which He gave,” etc. Why is it written in plural form?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the value of a person estimated for purposes of tzedakah (hekdesh)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which difficult word does Rashi say, "I don’t know Where it comes from”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we see that old age affects a man more negatively than it does a woman?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the saying brought from the Camera, describing the above conditions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done when a contributor cannot afford to pay the full value?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a person donate just the foot of an animal to the Beis Hamikdash? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that we may not exchange one animal (donated for a korban) for another, even one of equal value?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a donated animai that became blemishéd be redeemed? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we estimate the value of a field for redemption purposes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of dQnate-d (hekdesh) field returns to the owner in Yovei? Which doesn't?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of kosher and healthy animal cannot be donated to hekdesh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person donates a. tomei (non-kosher) animal to hekdesh, What is done with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person donates his possessions Without specifying to Whom it is given, Who gets them? (Two opinions.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes donating the vaiue of a human to hekdesh is ineffective. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of maaser must be eaten in Ierusalem? How is it stated in the posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What difference is there Whether one redeems his own maaser or someone else’s?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of maaser is designated by using a whip? What is done with this maaser?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the tenth animal has a blemish, what is done with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is there a hint in these pesukim about Yud Shevat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who gets the of the i'ochecha (curses, purflshments)? Is he called up?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we say ‘Chazak’ at the end of every Chumash?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
