<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Kedoshim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How d0 we 0W that this parsha was said at te gathering of the nations? y?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You shall “me 0%,” ate. What kind of holiness is eant hem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">y does it say; "Each am should fear is mother and father”? isn’t a waman aigo obiigamd to {ear and honor parents? y is tax mentioned. here
                first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">{flow does one give kavod (henor) to parents? And OW is yimh (fear, respeci) expressed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">y is e com;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">nandment to observe Shabbos written next to honoring parents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">ich laws concerning korbanos do we derive from pesukim 5—8?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">ich gifts to the poor are mentioned in pesukim</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"You shall not steal," etc. How does this prohibition difier from. the one in {he</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">mmandments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">is a logical connection between the pwhibitions in pesukim 11~12? What is the waming given concerning the wages 05 a worker?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not curse {he deaf.” Are we allowed; to curse othexs?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t put an obstacle in front 0% a. blind person.” at kind of obstacle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kinds of prohibitions does the Torah commonly add, “and you shall {ear Hashem”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of warnings are judges given in posuk 15?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvos and warne'mgs are given about rebukmg a friend?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the diiference between the sins of 161511011 horah and rechilus?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What else i5 forbidden along with the prohibition against revenge?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a prohibifion heee against being assive. In which situation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">ich three types of mixtures (shatnez) are prohibited here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">at are the three phases concerning the fruits of a newly planfied free? What kinds of magic are prohibited in posuic 72 (Ch. 20 and 19/
                27)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many fiansgressions are committed when shaving with a razor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the prohibitions concern'mg a pexson's skin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one Show respect to an old person? To a scholar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What warnings are given here concerning weights and measures?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for cursing parents? For adultery? For a homosexual act?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the animal killed when a human commits a sin with it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What moral lesson do we derive from it, according to Rashi?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And separated you from the nations to be Mine.” What iesson of conduct does Rabbi Elazar ben Azarya derive from this?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
