<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Tazria</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are the laws affecting humans written after the laws of animals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long is a woman tomei after the birth of a son? A daughter?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is her impure period stated as ’in clear blood’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of korbanos does a. wsman have to bring when she is cleansed? Which one of her korbanos actually cauées her to become taker"
                (pure)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can any rabbi decide whether negayim are tomei or tahor? Prod?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many hairs have to change to white in order to make the person tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which statement does Rashi comment, "I don’t know its meaning”? Why? In which case is the person declared tomei immediately? When is he
                locked up? When is a person locked up for a second time? For how long?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes the person is declared tahor yet must wash (towel) himself and his clothes. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After being locked up what has to happen to his negah to make him tomei? Tabor? What is the general difference between these: s'ais, sapachas,
                baheres?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May a Kohein decide on a person with a negah by getfing iormétion about its condition? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is it possible that a person could become tahor even While he has a regular tzoraas? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are certain days and certain people that a Kohein should refuse to check. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the signs of tumah for a negah on the skin? On the head?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Kohein mistakerfiy declares a. person 'tahor’ WhO is really tome-i, is it OK? Explain these: nesek, bohak, tzareves, keireiach,
                giveiach.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is a metzorah supposed to do to his clothes? To his hair? What does he announce? What kind of clothes (matelrials) can deveiop negayim?
                ‘What colors are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with a garment that became tomei?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Wheri is the negah supposed to be washed? If the negah's coloring remains the same what is done to it? And if the negah darkened
                somewhat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If after washing ii, it reappears again what" is done to the beged (garment)? If the negah was removed after washing it, what is done to the
                beged?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are there negayim today? Why? How is this connected to the Golus (Exile)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
