<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Devarim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why doesn’t Moshe state his words of rebuke <emphasis role="bold">clearly</emphasis> instead of just hinting?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“To all the Jews,” etc. Why was it necessary to gather them <emphasis role="bold">all</emphasis> here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which words hint at the following sins of Bnei Yisroel:</para>
            <orderedlist numeration="upperalpha">
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Making the golden calf</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Their complaints about the mon</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Their complaints at the Yam Suf</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Their idol worship of Peor</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">The rebellion of Korach</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">The sin of the spies</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe choose to rebuke them only when he was at the end of his life?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who else before and after Moshe rebuked close to his last days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“After he conquered Sichon and Og,” etc. Was this necessary for the rebuke? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which date did Moshe begin his review of the Torah? For how long?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe explain the Torah to them? (In what language?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the River Pross called the ‘Great River’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I cannot carry you by myself,” etc. Why? Who else said the same? For the same reason?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is meant by, “And you are today like the stars”? That many?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Come and inherit the land,” etc. But didn’t they have to prepare weapons and <emphasis role="bold">fight</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“He should add upon you a thousand fold.” Why does it then say, “and bless you”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How were some Jews uncooperative in court cases? In their view of Moshe’s conduct?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What example from a banker is given to explain the two kinds of ‘wise men’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe say get me judges (candidates) <emphasis role="bold">who are known to your tribes</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On whom are the nation’s failures blamed? Why? Is Moshe included?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Moshe’s complaint about Bnei Yisroel’s response on the appointment of judges?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And <emphasis role="bold">I took</emphasis> the heads of your tribes,” etc. How did he <emphasis role="bold">take</emphasis> them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were seven qualities of good judges. How many were found? Which one is missing here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which precaution for judges is mentioned here that is also mentioned in Pirkei Avos, Ch. 1?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of honors are the people obligated to display for the judges?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">To whom is this warning directed: “Don’t recognize faces (favorites) in judgment?” </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Listen to large and small alike,” etc. What are the <emphasis role="bold">three</emphasis> meanings here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a wrong judgment affect Hashem? Why is it mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe and Shmuel were both punished for putting themselves above others. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In how many aspects do monetary and capital court cases differ?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Mention is made here of two episodes when a mass of people approached Moshe. One was done properly and one was not. When? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe says <emphasis role="bold">he</emphasis> liked the idea of spying the land. Why then is he rebuking them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The report of the spies is presented here differently than before. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the people say that Hashem doesn’t like them? Was it true? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The fact that we got Eretz Yisroel was disliked by some people. Why? What example of two fields is used here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe said to them: “Don’t be afraid!” What proofs did he offer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where did Hashem clearly show that he treated us like a father?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What part of the land did Kalev receive? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe makes a point that the people were wrong about their children. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And they pursued you like the bees do.” What’s the comparison?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Hashem, <emphasis role="bold">the Merciful One</emphasis> didn’t listen to you.” Why the emphasis here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There was a place where the people dwelt as long as in all the others combined (during their travels in the desert). Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I will not give you even a footstep of their land.” Whose land? Why is the expression ‘footstep’ used here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Avrohom received ten lands from Hashem. Which now and which later?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Lot got two of these lands for now, because of a good deed. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe told them not to hide their riches in front of the nations. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Two warnings were given to our nation against attacking two nations. How? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was the removal of the old generation speeded up in the desert?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that Hashem’s spirit rests on the prophet <emphasis role="bold">only</emphasis> in honor of Bnei Yisroel.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The people called <glossterm>Refayim</glossterm> (why?) lived in two lands. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The people called <glossterm>Kaftorim</glossterm> destroyed the people called <glossterm>Avim</glossterm>. Why is this mentioned here? -</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the sun stopped in the sky for Moshe as it did for Yehoshua.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe figure out that it is proper to offer peace to Sichon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Hashem says to Moshe, “Look, <emphasis role="bold">I started giving you Sichon</emphasis> and his land.” How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Hashem cause Sichon to reject Moshe’s peace offer? With which other king did Hashem do the same thing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Sichon ask Og to help him in his battle against the Jews?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">in both wars against Sichon and Og, the Jews took lots of spoils but they felt differently about them. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In the war on Og, Moshe was told not to fear the enemy, but not in the war on Sichon. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Mount Chermon (now in Israel's hands) had four names. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
