<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Behaaloscha</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is this parsha written right next t0 the pal-aha of the nesiyim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Rashi gives two reasons why the word behaaioscha is used. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the meaning of the mitzvoh, “toward the frank oi the enmah,” etc? The reason for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"And Ahamn did so,” etc. at compliment is given to Aharon here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Meghe shown a mode} of the menorah? Haw was it made?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Take the Levi’im,” etc. How was he supposed to take them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why were they supposed to sprinkle special water on the Levi’im? And Why did they have to shave off ail of their hair?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The Levi’im had to bring two oxen for korbanos. Why? at was unusual} about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did the whole community have to gather at the dedication of the Levi’im?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word tenufah (lifting) mentioned here three times?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are there differences in words of the pesukim in connection with the lifting?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Because the firstborn are Mine,’ etc. How? Why is it menticned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is ’Bnei Yisroei’ mentioned five times in one posuk (8/ 19)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe, Aharon, and the tribes participated in the dedication of the Levi’im. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Different conditions disqualify Kohanim and Levi’im. What are these conditions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In one place it says that Levi’im start from age 25, in another it says from 30. Which is 1%?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long should a person study to see Whether he really has the potential? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At the age of 50 what can a Levi do? What can": he do?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Frove that there is no chronological order in the Torah.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t this Chumash (Bamidbar) start with the subject 0f Korban Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can the Korban Pesach be brought on Shabbos? If most people are impure? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When did Moshe Rabeinu tell the people about the laws of the holidays?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the argument of the people who were tomei and wanted to bring the Korban Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special praise of Moshe do we learn from the answer Moshe gave them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why wasn’t this parsha about the ’Pesach Sheini’ given by Moshe to begin with?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of people are obligated to bring the I’esach Sheini? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which aspects of the two kinds of Korban Pesach are like and unlike each other?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for totally missing the Korban Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which other h‘ansgression of a mitzvah asei (positive mitzvoh) gets this punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person converts to IudaiSIn after Pesach, does he bring a Pesach Sheini?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What were the signals for the tribes to travel and to rest?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When were the two trumpets used and when was only one used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we derive the need to recite Malchiyos, Zichronos, and Shofros?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much time did the people stay at Har Sinai?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At which point was the Mishkan taken apart for travelling?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who travelled ahead, Gershon, Kehos, or Mercri? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the special task of sheivet Don? Where was their position?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the two opinions on the formation of the cemp while travelling? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many names did Yisro have? Give reasons for two of them.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What proposition did Moshe put to his father-in-law? Reason?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was Yisro's reply? What were his two reasons?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which promises did Moshe offer to his father-in»law?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The city of Yericho had a very fertile space of 500 x 590 names. What was decided to do with it? Who got it meanwhile? But Yisro went
                home?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">They travelled unusually fas’; this time. How fast? Why this miracle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which aron kodesh traveiled ahead of them? for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many clouds were with them? Proof? What purpose did they serve?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe say Whenever they travelled? Why? Where do we recite it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There were two types of enemies. Which? What was Moshe's request about them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why are they called ’Hashem's enemies’? Why is this prayer written here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What number of Iews need there be for Hashem’s Presence to be among them? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the people called. in the Torah when they misbehave? When they are good?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was their complaint here? Its purpose? Who got burned for it? (Two opinions.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didsthey cry out to Moshe and not to Hashem? What happened to the fire?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Who will giye us meat?” Prove that this request was not justified.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did they really get fish from the Egyptians for free? Why? What did they mean?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The moh could taste like anything. Why, then, were they hungry for cucumbers, eta?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was iheir conflict about the men? What was the response to them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"Moshe heard the nation crying with their families,” etc. Why were they crying?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What 'c'omplaint’ did Mcshe voice to Hashem abcu’c the peoplc? What did he request?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Hashem said to Moshe, ’Gather up 70 Elders.’ “ But didn’t he already have 70 Elders?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which '70 people was Moshe looking for now? Where should he take them to? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When was Moshe compared to a woman (physical weakness)? When to a candle?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the conversation between Hashem and Moshe concerning the slaughtering of meat and the providing of fish according to Rabbi. Akiva and
                Rabbi Shimon, and Rabbi Gamliel.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">"They said proyhecy,” etc. (11/ 25) What are the two opinions about it (according to Rashi)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did Moshe pick the 70 judges from the tweive tribes?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
