<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Ki Savo</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When did the people start to bring bikurim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many kinds of produce are obligated in bikurim? Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Fruits don’t ripen at the same time. How does a person know which to take?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a person read the parsha and bring bikurim twice a year? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the purpose of bringing bikurim? And reading the parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Did Lavan actually harm Yaakov? How does the Torah say it? How does Hashem treat us differently than other nations?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where are the bikurim brought? What is done with them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which of Hashem’s favors to us are listed here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When else do we read this portion (pesukim 5-8) besides this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which time of the year is the proper season to bring bikurim? After that? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do the Levi’im bring bikurim? Converts? What about saying the parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is the time to clean out the tithes (<glossterm>maasros</glossterm>) and say <glossterm>Vidui</glossterm> (confession statement)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the order for the giving of the various maasros? During the six years?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the third year (in the six-year cycle) called ‘the maaser year’ (in the singular form)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When the maasros are cleaned out of the house the owner must say Vidui. What are the two positive and two negative things he mentions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I did <emphasis role="bold">according</emphasis> to <emphasis role="bold">your commandment</emphasis>,” etc. (26:13) What specifically is mentioned
                here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I didn’t transgress your commandments,” etc. Which aveiros did he <emphasis role="bold">not do</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Look out from your holy abode,” etc. What request is made here? The connection?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What message came by Heavenly voice (<glossterm>bas kol</glossterm>) to the Bikurim-bringer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Pesukim 17-19 tell of reciprocal actions between Hashem and us. What?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When they crossed the Yarden, they had to do two mitzvos with stones. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which shevatim were on Mount Evol and which on Grizim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where were the Levi’im and the holy Ark? What were the Levi’im doing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many curses were pronounced? On which aveiros?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the tribe of Shimon singled out here? What are we to learn from it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The last warning (curse) was of a general nature. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Divide the blessings (In 28:1-14) into four categories.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which particular blessing among the above is particularly related to Rosh Hashonoh? (Hint: the customs of Rosh Hashonoh night)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the customs in reading the Tochecha in shul?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What curses were said concerning the donkey, the ox, and the sheep?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a curse about borrowing money. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The first set of curses appears in parshas Bechukosai (in sefer Vayikra). What is the difference between them and those in our parsha (in
                severity and number)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give one example to show that the curses here are more lenient.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is one posuk that gives a reason for these curses. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Someone (something) is compared to the swiftness of an eagle. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">These curses and punishments are compared to some that Bnei Yisroel saw. Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection are <emphasis role="bold">boats</emphasis> mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“A heart to understand and eyes to see until this day.” What reaction of Bnei Yisroel proved that <emphasis role="bold">now</emphasis> they truly
                appreciated the Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why will the responsibility of the Jewish nation become bigger and more serious from now on (referring to question 38)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When does a talmid truly understand his Rebbe’s words? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the significance of reading this parsha at year’s end?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that understanding Torah and seeing things right is a gift from Hashem.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Special</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="43">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does the 18th of Elul mean to you? How does that make <emphasis role="bold">you</emphasis> feel proud?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you find a connection between this parsha and this month?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do you know the story of how the Alter Rebbe used to read this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
