<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Pesach</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are five mitzvos performed during the Seder. Which are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is <glossterm>shmurah</glossterm> (hand-baked) matzo better than machine matzo?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Must everyone at the Seder table understand the whole Haggadah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we drink <emphasis role="bold">four</emphasis> cups of wine? How much of the cup must we drink?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which other beverages may one drink (in special cases)? What is preferred?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much should children drink? Women? How big is a ‘cup’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many portions of matzo must one eat through the Seder?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In how short a time-period should one eat each portion of matzo? Drink each cup?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we eat <glossterm>marror</glossterm> at the Seder? How much must one eat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of herbs are kosher for marror? Which is preferable?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Lettuce is not bitter; why is it kosher for marror?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How should one prepare the romaine lettuce for marror? When should it be prepared?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are children required to eat manor? Could it be grated or chopped?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we have to recline (lean) at the Seder? To which side?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which activities must we recline? When is it optional?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a left-handed person recline? Does a son recline near a father? A student near a Torah teacher?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which items are put on the Seder plate? In what formation?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we take <emphasis role="bold">three</emphasis> matzos? What are their titles?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we take for <glossterm>zroah</glossterm> (according to the Lubavitcher custom)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the <glossterm>charoses</glossterm> prepared? The salt water? Why do we eat less than a kezayis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When one eats the <glossterm>korech</glossterm> (sandwich) can he <emphasis role="bold">swallow</emphasis> matzo and marror separately?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we have to eat korech? What do we say when we eat it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should one’s kavana be when drinking the kiddush wine? The other three cups?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we wash our hands for karpas? Why is there no brocho recited on this mitzvoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the karpas dipped in salt water? Why do we eat less than a kezayis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do we spill drops of wine when reciting the ten makes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">During which activities is it forbidden to talk during the Seder?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What general intention must one have when reciting the Haggadah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one dip the matzos in wine or soup? Drink <emphasis role="bold">while</emphasis> eating matzo?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When must we eat the Afikoman? How <emphasis role="bold">full</emphasis> must we be before it? How much of it do we eat?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should one do after the Seder?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do the bechorim fast if the first day of Pesach falls on a Sunday? When is a <glossterm>siyum</glossterm> made?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which new mitzvoh do we start on the second night of Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is changed in the Shmoneh Esrei beginning on Chol Hamoed? What is added?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the best activity during Chol Hamoed?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the Havdala on Sunday night different than on a regular Shabbos night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which portions of the Torah are read on Chol Hamoed? Is tefillin used on Chol Hamoed? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the last day of Pesach differ in the eating of the matzo?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Shabbos Hagadol called by that name? (See how many reasons you can give.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times do we light candles during this Yom Tov? Do we make an eruv tavshillin?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para dir="ltr"><emphasis role="bold">THE PROHIBITIONS OF CHAMETZ</emphasis></para>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="41">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On Pesach, there are three positive mitzvos and five negative ones. What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How are the prohibitions of chametz different from those of non-kosher foods?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">From which <emphasis role="bold">time</emphasis> is chametz prohibited to eat? To keep? To benefit from?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a Jew had chametz in his possession during Pesach what happens to that chametz?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is <glossterm>gebrokts</glossterm>? Why do we avoid it? Why do some eat it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which foods is there a difference of customs between Sefardim and Ashkenazim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can we use regular soaps and detergents on Pesach? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can powders (talcum powder, baby powder, etc.) be used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are (medical) tablets or liquid permitted where there is no danger? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special problem of medicine capsules? How is it solved?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which liquids should not be used on Pesach? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can we shop in a private grocery or in a supermarket (for items containing chametz) right after Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special problem of chametz is there in ketchup, mayonnaise, etc?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sugar, salt, tea and coffee — do they need a special <glossterm>hechsher</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special care should be used in obtaining milk, butter and cheese?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do some people use only <emphasis role="bold">unwashed</emphasis> eggs? Why do some not use <emphasis role="bold">garlic</emphasis>? What about
                    <emphasis role="bold">dried fruits</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why do people have so many <glossterm>chumrahs</glossterm> (restrictions) on Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did the Ari Zal say about the reward for extra care on Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper procedure for eating fresh fruit and vegetables?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which are the two (general) methods for koshering dishes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Not all metal dishes can be koshered. Which <emphasis role="bold">cannot</emphasis> be koshered?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you kosher dishes from milchigs to fleishigs?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can dishes made of <emphasis role="bold">plastic</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">melmac</emphasis>, or <emphasis role="bold">teflon</emphasis> be
                koshered?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How about dishes made of <emphasis role="bold">Corningware</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">Pyrex</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                    >duralex</emphasis>? Glass?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can dishes made of china, porcelain, or enamel be koshered?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"><emphasis role="bold">Dish towels</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">tablecloths</emphasis> that were washed, can they be used?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can spoons, forks and <emphasis role="bold">knives</emphasis> be koshered? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should one avoid 24 hours before koshering any dish?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does one kosher a kitchen sink? A kitchen range?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the proper ways to kosher microwave, self-cleaning, gas, and electric ovens?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">People who have false teeth, dentures, etc. — how do they prepare for Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kind of dishes must be immersed in a mikvah? What is the brocho?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we make a <glossterm>bitul chametz</glossterm>, <glossterm>biyur chametz</glossterm>, <glossterm>mechiras chametz</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What must be done in the home by the time bedikas chametz arrives?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What activities are prohibited within one half-hour prior to bedikas chametz? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which places must be searched for chametz? Which ‘tools’ are used for the bedikah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Until when may we eat chametz on the morning of Erev Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person leaves his house before the bedikah night what must he do about bedikas chametz?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the difference between the bitul chametz at night and in the morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one eat matzo products on Erev Pesach?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
