<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Rosh HaShonoh</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is Rosh Hashonoh called in the Torah? Why? What was created on that day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the sgeciai things we do (or say) on Erev Rash Hashonoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How should we spemi the rest of the time on Erev Rosh Hashonoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When Rosh Hashono comes out on a Thursday, What is done on Tuesday and Thursday but not on Wednesday? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Must one stay awake. Rosh Hashonoh night? Rosh Hashonoh day? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of foods do we customarily eat Rosh Hashonoh night? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On "which food do we (Lubavitchers) say Ratzon? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we say it (before or after the brocho)? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the exact Wish we use Rosh Hashonoh night (in Hebrew)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we Wish the same by day? Why? What is said?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of foods do we avoid eatmg on Rosh Hashonoh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May one eat on Rosh Hashonoh before daverfing? Drink? Go to the mikvah? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the best things to do before the morning davening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mistake in davening the Shmoneh Esrei requims repetition?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is Halls! said on Rosh Hashonoh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What part is read. in the Torah on Rosh Hashonoh (both days)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are the Rash Hashonoh Zm'm'ng ‘trop’ (cantiHation/musical notes) the same as on Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the titles of the person who blows the shofar and the one Who points in the Machzor to the kinds of sounds that should be blown (or
                reads them) to him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many kinds of sounds do we biow with the shofar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When else do we blow the shofar besides after krias kaTomh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many sounds do we blow in all (before going home)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should the listeners say and not say when they hear the brochos on the shofar? What are the two brochos on the shofar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What shouid listeners have in mind when they begin to listen (to the</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In connection with the shofar, from When and until when must we avoid talking? at: “HULL. .1 -' 1</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the main 'message' of the sound of shofar? (See Rambam.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are at least ten reasons (from Reb Sadya Gaon) for the mitzvoh of shofar. How many do you know?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we bow down on the floor during the davening?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person wants to biow the shofar for others (for men or women), when and how is the best time and way to do it? (What are the problems in
                this activity?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we do (and say) Tashlich? What are_ the reasons for it? (Give three or four.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After Minchah, when Tashlich is done, what should one do till Maariv?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there a need for a new fruit on the second night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When is that fruit eaten? Must you eat a kezayis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kinds of work are forbidden on Rosh Hashonoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kinds of work are permitted? Is smoking permitted?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a gas fire be put on? Put out? Made bigger? Smaller?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the emv tavshillin? How is it done? When? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if a person forgot to do it? Does a bochur have to do it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of a mood is proper for Rosh Hashonoh (before and after dawning)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we make Kiddush Rosh Hashonoh by day? By night?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we maké Havdala at the end of Yam Tov? (“That if it’s Friday night?)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the name of the Shabbos following Rash Hashonoh? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the Torah reading for this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Besides the Machzor, which book is used most on Rash Hashonoh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When Rosh Hashono comes out on a Thursday, Why is Sunday a fast day? Are Selichos said? Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When does the fast start and when does it finish?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is exempt from fasting? Do children fast?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the special additions in davening for Aseres Yemei Teshuvah (Ten Days of Repentance)? Do we say Seiichos? Do other shuis say it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Generally what special precautions are therefor these days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the name (number) of the new year?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper Wish to be expressed right after Rush Hashonoh (in Hebrew)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Exialainz</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Ikkiah</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Teruah</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Shevarim</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Tekias di’me’umad</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Tekias di'meyushav 391.51%)"; 03191</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Me’ah kolos</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Kesivah vachasimah tovah</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Gemar chasimah tovah</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Le’aifer Zechayim</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Sifron she! tzadikim, Shofms</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Shpnoh tough umesukah</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Malchiyos, zichronos</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para dir="ltr">Haioms nedarim</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
