<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Yom Kippur</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is <glossterm>Kapores</glossterm> done (best) early in the morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one do Kapores with things other than chickens? If yes, with what?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What mitzvoh is available at the time of the slaughtering?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if the slaughtering went wrong, do you have to get another chicken?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the idea behind the custom of Kapores?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with the slaughtered Kapores? (Two possibilities.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the important mitzvoh on <emphasis role="bold">Erev</emphasis> Yom Kippur? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Certain sins are not forgiven on Yom Kippur. Which? What can we do for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On Erev Yom Kippur we go to the mikvah three times (if possible). When are these done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">All men should get <glossterm>makos</glossterm> (floggings) on Erev Yom Kippur. How? When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Lots of tzedakah is given on Erev Yom Kippur (according to your ability). Could you use maaser?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We ask for honey-cake (<glossterm>lekach</glossterm>) on Erev Yom Kippur. Why? From whom?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much does one have to eat on Erev Yom Kippur? When is this done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The meal before the fast has a special name. What? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is definitely avoided at this meal (though it’s important at the earlier meal)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">It is best to finish the late meal at least one half-hour before sunset. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If is an important custom for parents to bless their children after candle-lighting (or close to it). Could you do it on the phone? Will you ask
                for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If you want to eat or drink or brush your teeth after that meal, can you?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give two reasons for the custom or wearing (for married men) a <glossterm>kittel</glossterm> (white robe/coat) on Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the content of <glossterm>Kol Nidrei</glossterm>? Why is it so important?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Before Kol Nidrei we quietly say the Vidui. This is the <emphasis role="bold">second</emphasis> time, When was the first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The second posuk of Shma (<glossterm>‘Baruch Shem’</glossterm>) is said <emphasis role="bold">loudly</emphasis> on Yom Kippur. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When we say the long Vidui we mention sins we might not personally have done. Why do we say them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many times of prayer do we have on Yom Kippur? What are their names?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do we read in the Torah in the morning and at Minchah time on Yom Kippur? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Maftir Yonah is very famous for being read at Minchah time; some people offer large sums for tzedakah to bid for it. What story is told there?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The number of aliyos is greater on Yom Kippur than other holidays. How many are there? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We say <glossterm>Yizkor</glossterm> (after the first Torah reading) on Yom Kippur. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what ways is Yom Kippur like Shabbos (instead of like Yam Tov)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the five personal physical needs that are forbidden on Yom Kippur? When is one <emphasis role="bold">allowed</emphasis> to wash (hands,
                etc.)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is exempt from fasting?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why isn’t Yom Kippur observed for two days as are the other Yomim Tovim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the main mitzvoh for the day of Yom Kippur?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the proper moods for us on Erev Yom Kippur and on Yom Kippur itself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At the end of the day’s prayers we repeat some pesukim. Which one do we do three times?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should we have in mind when we say Shma at day’s end? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we blow the shofar (one tekiah) at day’s end? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When do we sing the joyous victory march and dance? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">At day’s end we say something about Jerusalem. What? What do they say in Jerusalem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper greeting at the end of Yom Kippur? And in the days after?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">May we eat after Maariv? Meat? When do we wash <glossterm>negel vasser</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Weather permitting, we do <glossterm>Kiddush Levana</glossterm> after Maariv. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the Shmoneh Esrei of this Maariv different from the Shmoneh Esrei of the past ten days?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the most desirable activity after breaking the fast?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these terms:</para>
            <simplelist columns="2">
                <member>A. <glossterm>Avodah</glossterm></member>
                <member>B. <glossterm>Ne’ilah</glossterm></member>
                <member>C. <glossterm>Duchenen</glossterm></member>
                <member>D. <glossterm>Kohein Gadol</glossterm></member>
                <member>E. <glossterm>Asara harugei malchus</glossterm></member>
                <member>F. <glossterm>Chamisha inuyim</glossterm></member>
                <member>G. <glossterm>Kori’in</glossterm></member>
                <member>H. <glossterm>Tevilohs</glossterm></member>
                <member>I. <glossterm>Bigdei lavan</glossterm></member>
                <member>J. <glossterm>Bigdei zahav</glossterm></member>
                <member>K. <glossterm>Sei’ir la’azazel</glossterm></member>
                <member>L. <glossterm>Gemar chasimah tovah</glossterm></member>
            </simplelist>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
