<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="ki-seitzei" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Ki Seitzei</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many types of war are discussed in the Torah? Which one is mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a person from the ‘seven nations’ is captured, can he be used as a servant?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“The Torah only spoke (here) against the yetzer horah.” Were is this applied?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Besides conversion, what are the other things the captured women must do to marry?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What will be the future of this kind of marriage according to the Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of children is this woman likely to have? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The oldest brother takes a double portion. But sometimes he doesn’t. When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The rebellious son (<glossterm>ben sorer umoreh</glossterm>) gets the death penalty. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Previously he got a lesser punishment. What was it? What crimes did he commit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the next subject in the Torah connected to that of the ben sorer umoreh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason is given for honoring the body of even a sinful person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one sees a lost item on the street may he just ignore it (look away)? Ever?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a lost animal is found, should he be sold or kept (in order to be returned)? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if you find a wallet on yeshiva grounds - can you use it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what case can you be exempt from helping a Jew to lift a load?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of prohibition is there on men’s and women’s garments?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If someone tells you the location of a bird nest, can you go there to do a mitzvoh of <glossterm>shiluach hakan</glossterm>? Reason?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can one take (and use) the mother bird <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> sending her off? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the reward for this mitzvoh? How about ‘harder’ mitzvos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the connection between the parshiyos of shiluach hakan, <glossterm>kilayim</glossterm> (mixing seeds), kilayim in plowing, kilayim in garments,
                and tzitzis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the man was destined to get hurt why should the house owner make a fence?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which manner of planting grain and vines is forbidden by the Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is <emphasis role="bold">incorrect</emphasis> in this statement, “Only an ox with a donkey are forbidden to be used together, and only in
                planting.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the mitzvoh of tzitzis written following the prohibition of shatnez?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that one aveiro leads to another. How is this stated in Pirkei Avos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Torah considers a child’s (even a grown child’s) behavior a reflection of his or her upbringing.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the two penalties for a <glossterm>motzi sheim rah</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who is punished more severely, an engaged women or a married woman who sinned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“A break in the wall (of modesty) invites the criminal.” Where is this exempt?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that forcing someone to sin is considered like killing him.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that when you’re really forced into an aveiro, you are exempt from punishment. What is the Hebrew term for this kind of aveiro? Other
                kinds?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of (Jewish) person may never marry a Jew (by birth)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Two reasons are stated why men (only) from Amon and Moav may not marry Jewish women.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Edomite and Egyptian converts may marry Jews a little later. When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the Torah more strict with Amon and Moav than with the Egyptians?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the Torah wants us to be thankful for a favor eternally</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the one who causes a person to sin is doing a bigger harm than if he had killed him. Give a reason for your answer.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Someone who did good things to you at first, but then became cruel to you — should you remember both, forget both, or remember one? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Nowadays, if an Egyptian convert wants to marry a Jew, may he (or she)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is special care to avoid tumah necessary in war-time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A person must keep the area around him clean even in hard times. Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the right thing to do if a runaway slave comes to you?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give a case where a good, healthy lamb is disqualified for a korban.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many aveiros are done when one takes <emphasis role="bold">interest</emphasis> from a Jew?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When promising to bring a korban as a donation, how long may you delay it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A person who is working in someone’s vineyard, may he eat lots of grapes?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a divorce (<glossterm>get</glossterm>) proceed? May the divorced couple remarry each other?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The first year of marriage, the exemption from the draft is bigger than other exemptions. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of security (for a loan) may not be taken? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If someone kidnaps a Jew and sells him, what is his punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There was a great tragedy in our history that was connected to the above. Can you guess which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Miriam’s leprosy mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what <emphasis role="bold">manner</emphasis> are we forbidden to take security (<glossterm>mashkon</glossterm>) from the borrower?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Sometimes we must keep returning the security daily. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a difference in the gravity of the aveiro of withholding wages from a rich worker or a poor one? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a difference whether a verdict is tilted for a rich or a poor man?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the exodus from Mitzrayim mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is one mitzvoh which can <emphasis role="bold">never</emphasis> be done with kavana! Which?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Do we give <glossterm>pe’ah</glossterm> from fruit trees? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is <emphasis role="bold">incorrect</emphasis> in this statement: The prohibition against muzzling (closing the mouth) of animals is applicable only
                ‘for an ox while he threshes the grain’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the subject of <glossterm>malkos</glossterm> written next to the above prohibition?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that it is against the Torah law to hit a person (even a bad person).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what cases does the mitzvoh of <glossterm>yibum</glossterm>
                <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> apply?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And where does <glossterm>chalitzah</glossterm> apply? How is it done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is Amalek compared to?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is it written next to the section on correct weights?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that cheating in business brings losses and honesty brings blessings.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
