<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="nitzavim" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Nitzavim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You are standing today,” etc. Where was this? When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what order are all the groups of Jews mentioned here? How many categories are there?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who were the ‘wood choppers’ and ‘water-carriers’ that are mentioned here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What was the common manner of making a covenant?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is Hashem warning us so much and making strong covenants?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does parshas Nitzavim appear right after parshas Ki Savo?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How did the Jewish people react to hearing the 98 curses?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason for this gathering is connected with the appointment of Yehoshua?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was included in the covenant now who wasn’t present then?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">They saw the wooden and stone idols but not the golden ones. Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that the yetzer horah can make even the repulsive seem attractive.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The reason for this oath and covenant is that there might be someone who feels ‘differently’ than most people. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">That person will pay even for the aveiros which were disregarded before. Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the aveiros of shogeig called? Meizid?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What will that person think in his heart about the results of his actions?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What does Hashem promise to do to this kind of a person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The last generation (why ‘last’?) and the stranger will ask a big question about the condition of our land. Which question?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What answer will be offered to them? Who answers it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Will the many suffer for the hidden sins of the individual? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And for his open sins, were they <emphasis role="bold">always</emphasis> responsible? Why? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What new condition and resolution developed in Mount Grizim and Evol is true today?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can you find a source for doing mivtzoyim in this posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a prediction here that the nation will repent. When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When He will gather us from exile, He Himself will also ‘return.’ Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is another reason why it is written about redemption in a special way?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“It is not in Heaven,” etc. What if the Torah were to be in Heaven?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“For it is close to you,” etc. What makes the Torah close to us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the principle of ‘free choice’ stated here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What parable is given to explain the need for telling us, “and you shall choose life?”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Does a person choose ‘good’ in order to have ‘life’, or does he choose ‘life’ and does the ‘good’ to deserve life? (Prove it from the pesukim.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Heaven and earth will be your witnesses,” etc. Why do we need witnesses?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What lesson can Jews learn from the earth and the Heaven?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Special</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="33">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a posuk here that hints to Elul. Which posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">To which <emphasis role="bold">avodah</emphasis> of Elul does it refer?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a posuk here which is central to Tanya. Which posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
