<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="shoftim" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Shoftim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kinds of appointments (positions) are mentioned in the first posuk? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where are the courts supposed to be set up?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does bribery affect the judge that receives it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t tilt (turn) the judgment and don’t show favoritism.” Why is there a need for both warnings?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the reward for appointing proper judges?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Justice, justice you shall pursue,” etc. (16:20) What is commanded here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is forbidden to build or plant on the Temple Mount?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What type of structure was once beloved but then disliked by Hashem? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t slaughter. ..any <emphasis role="bold">bad thing</emphasis>,” etc. What is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for a man or woman who serves idols (the sun or moon)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is their guilt proven? Who punishes them first?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Through two or three witnesses.” If two are enough, why are three mentioned?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which kinds of <emphasis role="bold">problems</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">arguments</emphasis> are judges advised to bring their questions
                to the Sanhedrin in Jerusalem?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And to the judge that will be <emphasis role="bold">in those days</emphasis>,” etc. What does this teach us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t deviate (turn)... left or <emphasis role="bold">right</emphasis>.” Why is it stated this way?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the punishment for the one who refuses to listen to the Sanhedrin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of person <emphasis role="bold">cannot</emphasis> be chosen for a king of our people?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A Jewish king has three prohibitions against increase. What are they? Reasons for two of these?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special positive mitzvoh a king has? What reason is given for it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What example is given from King Shaul on the results of ignoring the Prophets?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a special caution concerning the king’s heart. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does Rashi explain the terms, “the inheritance of the <emphasis role="bold">five</emphasis>, and of the <emphasis role="bold"
                >seven</emphasis>”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">A special <emphasis role="bold">gift</emphasis> (tax) was given to the Kohein from every cattle. What? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How much terumah must one give to the Kohein? Shearings of wool?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How many lambs must one be shearing to be obligated in <glossterm>reishis hagez</glossterm>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can a Kohein work during a time which is not his <glossterm>mishmor</glossterm> (period)? Does he share in the korbanos if he did work? Explain.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not <emphasis role="bold">learn to do</emphasis> their abomination,” etc. Can you <emphasis role="bold">sometimes</emphasis> learn it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the following: <glossterm>kosem</glossterm>, <glossterm>me’onen</glossterm>, <glossterm>menachesh</glossterm>, <glossterm>mechashef</glossterm>,
                <glossterm>chover</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Because the non-Jewish nations do all of the above, they’re punished. How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the proper approach to life’s uncertainties, fitting for a Jew?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And yet Hashem gave us the Prophets. What for?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Hashem says we, the Jewish people, asked for Nevi’im. When?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There are six ways a Navi can violate his trust. For three of those violations he is punished by Hashem and for the other three by the court.
                What are they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How can we tell that a Navi is saying a prophecy which he <emphasis role="bold">was not</emphasis> commanded to say?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Who was Chananya ben Azur? What was his dispute with Yirmiyahu?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if a Navi comes to tell us to violate one of the mitzvos — do we listen?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Don’t be afraid of him.” What is the meaning of this admonition?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How are the roads to the cities of refuge prepared?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of act obligated a person to escape to the cities of refuge?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“If it happens in the course of chopping wood,” etc. What dispute is there about this among the Rabbis?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">And in the future we will get three more cities of refuge. When? How many in all?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done if an intentional murderer escapes to the cities of refuge? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And if someone will hate his fellow,” etc. What lesson is taught here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is the Torah for capital punishment or against it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If someone moves over a boundary separation, which sins does he commit?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which cases is a single witness effective and in which not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">By what statement can a second pair of witnesses <emphasis role="bold">totally eliminate</emphasis> the first pair?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When giving testimony in the court, the Witnesses must not do it the wrong way. What are the wrong ways? (Three examples.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Yiftach in his generation is like Shmuel in his.” What is meant by this?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When are the <emphasis role="bold">contradicted witnesses</emphasis> (<glossterm>edim zomemin</glossterm>) punished? How? When not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which case is it said that the edim zomemin are punished like the man but not like the woman?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Are the witnesses punished privately or publicly? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“An eye for an eye,” etc. How is this done?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“When you go out to make war <emphasis role="bold">on your enemy</emphasis>,” etc. Why is this written <emphasis role="bold">here</emphasis>? And why
                emphasize ‘on your enemy’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Before going to war, the Kohein gave them four warnings. What were they?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which three categories are exempt from going to war?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does the Kohein begin his speech with the words, ‘Shma Yisroel’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does he emphasize that they’re going to do battle with <emphasis role="bold">their enemies</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What gives the Jews the assurance that they will be victorious?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is supposed to be done with a vineyard on the 4th year? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the dispute between Reb Akiva and Reb Yosi Ha’glili here? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Is there a fourth category of people who are exempt from the draft?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did they have to appoint special officers <emphasis role="bold">after</emphasis> the
                above warnings? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In an optional war (<glossterm>milchemes ho’rshus</glossterm>) what is done before attacking
                a city? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If an enemy city agrees to make peace, which are the conditions for it?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is done with the women, children, and possessions of a city which resists?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The seven nations of Can’aan, could they ever be accepted in our midst? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When approaching an enemy city, we must keep Shabbos in mind. How?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special prohibitions are stated concerning fruit trees?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What else does the above prohibitions include under the heading of <glossterm>baal
                    tashcis</glossterm>? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a dead body is found in the field, what is done about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which judges get involved in this problem? What do they measure?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which city must bring the <glossterm>egloh arufoh</glossterm> (the chopped-off calf)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is this kind of a calf chosen for this purpose? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Where is the chopping-off (of the calf) being done? Why? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What statement do the Elders make at this ceremony?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What do the Kohanim say at this setting?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if the murderer is found after all the above?
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Our hands didn’t spill this blood,” etc. Might we think <emphasis role="bold"
                    >they</emphasis> did it? </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What promise does the Torah give them after everything is done right?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
