<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xml:id="veyeilech" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Veyeilech</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“I cannot come and go any longer,” etc. Why? Could this be due to old age?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Again Hashem’s advice to Yehoshua on leadership, and Moshe’s, are mentioned. Tell the difference.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What did Moshe do with the Sefer Torah that he finished on his last day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvoh was done once in seven years? When is the next year?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When was the king the <glossterm>baal koreh</glossterm>? What did he read? On which spot?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did they bring infants to this event?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the meaning of the punishment, “I will hide My Presence on that day”?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Write down this shira,” “This shira will testify,” etc. Which one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What will be the testimony of this shira?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">There is a special positive guarantee that we and Torah got together. What is it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Take this Sefer Torah and put it at the <emphasis role="bold">side of the Ark</emphasis>.” What is the dispute among the Sages concerning this
                placement?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">One day when the Jews gathered, the trumpets were not used. Which day?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t Yehoshua use these trumpets?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which wise saying in Koheles (Ecclesiastes) is being applied here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does he repeat here again the testimony of Heaven and earth?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that to a Rebbi, his talmid is considered an extension of him (even physically). Why?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <bridgehead>Special</bridgehead>
    <orderedlist startingnumber="17">
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">On which weekday of Elul do we <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> blow the shofar?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What’s special about this Shabbos? About the next?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
