<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="vo-eschanan" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Vo’eschanan</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Tzadikim could make a request in two ways. Which is the right one?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“At that time,” etc. What was that appropriate time?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">This is one of <emphasis role="bold">three</emphasis> places where Moshe <emphasis role="bold">insisted</emphasis>. On what? Another place?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You started showing your servant,” etc. What did He show? When? (Two answers.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And Your strong Hand,” etc. Which Hand? What strength is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Besides seeing that ‘good land,’ in general, which specific things did he crave to see?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was Moshe told ‘enough for you.’ in response to his request?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was any part of Moshe’s request fulfilled? Which? How?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And <emphasis role="bold">command</emphasis> Yehoshua, and <emphasis role="bold">strengthen</emphasis> him,” etc. Command to do what? And why did he
                need special strengthening? How was Moshe to strengthen him?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the problem in the battle of Ei a result of Yehoshua’s failure?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And we sat in the valley across from Beis Peor,” “And how Israel observe the laws,” etc. What is the connection?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give examples for the prohibition, “Don’t add nor subtract from the mitzvos.”</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When the nations of the world will hear about our laws, what will they say about us?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Watch yourself, lest you forget” etc. What may happen as a result?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the warnings about images? About the sun and the moon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">We were exiled two years prior to a certain time. Which time? Was it a favor?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How are the events of Tisha B’Av predicted here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is considered ‘like worshiping idols’ even though it isn’t? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Ask, please, about the early days,” etc. (4:32) What should we learn from history?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How tall was Adam? “Was there ever such a <emphasis role="bold">great thing</emphasis>”? Which thing?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What are the examples given for these deeds: <glossterm>masos</glossterm>, <glossterm>osos</glossterm>, <glossterm>mofsim</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>milchamah</glossterm>? (See posuk 4:34.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“You have been <emphasis role="bold">shown to</emphasis> know that there is nothing besides G-d.” How was it shown?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In whose merit did we receive so many great favors? (Exodus from Egypt, Torah, Eretz Yisroel)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Then Moshe separated three cities” When did these cities separate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe want to separate them now? What is the lesson here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Do not have other gods <emphasis role="bold">before me</emphasis>.” When? Where?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Try to notice and mark down the differences between the first and second giving of the Ten Commandments. Example: the reasons for keeping
                Shabbos.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which one of Rashi’s comments on the Ten Commandments has been incorporated into the davening of Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which mitzvos were given to them before Matan Torah? Give two examples.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In posuk 5:19 it says “<glossterm>velo yosof</glossterm>.” What are the two meanings here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the Jews heard the divine voice from Har Sinai, they got fearful. Why? What did they request from Moshe? What did Hashem say about it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What ‘wish’ did Hashem express in connection with this request?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was Moshe happy about the request? Why? The proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does Rashi explain the great statement of “<glossterm>Shma Yisroel</glossterm>” (in posuk 1)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And you shall love Hashem,” etc. Why is it preferable to serve out of love rather than fear?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“With all your heart,” etc. What is this referring to? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is meant by “all your soul”? “All your might”? (Two meanings.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a person get to love Hashem (according to the context here)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is the word <glossterm>veshinantam</glossterm> used here for the study and teaching of Torah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is the relationship between a <glossterm>rebbi</glossterm> (teacher) and <glossterm>talmid</glossterm> (student) described here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And you shall speak (in) them,” etc. What does this add after saying it in the earlier posuk?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“When you go to sleep and when you wake up.” What mitzvoh is meant here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does the word <glossterm>totafos</glossterm> mean tefillin?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Prove that we aren’t obligated to put mezuzos on <emphasis role="bold">both</emphasis> doorposts.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kinds of gates require mezuzos? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What should the Jews expect to find when entering the Holy Land?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why is there an immediate <emphasis role="bold">warning</emphasis> following the above <emphasis role="bold">goodies</emphasis>?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Was this kind of warning mentioned elsewhere in this parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When may a man swear in Hashem’s name? Why only then?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And you shall do the righteous and the good,” etc. (6:18) What is asked of us here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Have our ancestors ever attempted to test Hashem? If yes, when? Why mention it here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“If your son shall ask you,” etc. Which son (of the ’four sons’) is written about here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What answer is given here? Is it the same as in the Haggadah?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Give three prohibitions about idol worship mentioned in the beginning of Chapter 7.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr"><emphasis role="bold">Hard question:</emphasis> Prove that a son of a Jewish mother and a non-Jewish father is considered Jewish, but not a son of a
                non-Jewish mother and Jewish father.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the differences: <glossterm>mizbeyach</glossterm>, <glossterm>matzeivo</glossterm>, <glossterm>ashairo</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>pesilim</glossterm>. (See posuk 7:6.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“Not because of your greatness (in population),” etc. What different traits of Jews and non-Jews are described here (according to the Midrash)?
                Examples?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two categories of tzadikim are mentioned in posuk 7:9?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How is His reward different for the above two kinds? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">His enemies also get rewarded. Why? Is it good for them?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Twice in the parsha is the word <glossterm>hayom</glossterm> (today) emphasized (“That I command you <emphasis role="bold">today</emphasis>”). What are
                the two messages here?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the special name and mood for this Shabbos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What special day occurs right in the middle of Av (its name, history and observance)?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
