<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Mishpatim</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“And these are the laws,” etc. What are the <emphasis role="bold">two</emphasis> connections to the previous parsha (Yisro)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In what connection is the term <glossterm>Shulchon Oruch</glossterm> mentioned in the first posuk? (See Rashi.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is wrong with bringing a dispute to the non-Jewish courts?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How was the <glossterm>eved Ivri</glossterm> (Jewish slave) purchased? Would the law be different if he sold himself?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of eved can get a <glossterm>shifcha Cnaanis</glossterm> (a gentile maidservant)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What happens to this shifcha Cnaanis after the eved goes free? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What if the eved Ivri refuses to leave until after six years?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Can an <glossterm>eved nirtza</glossterm> be a slave forever? Until when? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which ear is pierced? Why the <emphasis role="bold">ear</emphasis> (not the nose)? (Different reasons for different <glossterm>avodim</glossterm>,
                slaves).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The door and the door post are connected with piercing the ears. How? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which kind of child may the father sell into temporary slavery? Can a mother sell too?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do non-Jewish slaves (men and women) go free from slavery?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How does a young girl go free from slavery? (Three or four ways.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these terms: <glossterm>yi’ud</glossterm>, <glossterm>simanim</glossterm>, <glossterm>naarus</glossterm>, <glossterm>bagrus</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>sha’ir</glossterm>, <glossterm>kesus</glossterm>, <glossterm>onah</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which two laws in the punishment for killing do we derive from posuk 12?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why does Hashem make it happen that one person should kill another? Find a parallel to this thought in <glossterm>Pirkei Avos</glossterm> (Ethics of our
                Fathers).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If a doctor mistakenly kills his patient or a father his son are they punished? Source?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What reason would you give a doctor not to operate on his parents?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which person gets the death penalty just for saying some words?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of thief gets punished by death?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What kind of payments are required if one maimed a person?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain these terms: <glossterm>nezek</glossterm>, <glossterm>tzaar</glossterm>, <glossterm>ripui</glossterm>, <glossterm>sheves</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>boshes</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If the master (or a stranger) kills a non-Jewish slave, what is his punishment?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If one kills a pregnant woman, what is his punishment? What if she survived the attack?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">“An eye for an eye,” etc. How do we prove that it means monetary payment? (See Gemora Baba Kama p. 84.)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">The knocking out of a eye or a tooth sets a slave free. Which other limbs do the same?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">If someone’s lion (or chicken) kills a person, what happens to the animal? What happens to the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person’s ox kills another ox what happens to the owner?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Explain the terms: <glossterm>mazik</glossterm>, <glossterm>nizak</glossterm>, <glossterm>tam</glossterm>, <glossterm>mu’od</glossterm>,
                    <glossterm>kofer</glossterm>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When a person makes a pit (<glossterm>bor</glossterm>), which kind of damages is he responsible for?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
