<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Va'eira</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Moshe received rebuke (<glossterm>mussar</glossterm>) from Hashem. Proof? Why was he rebuked?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When the Torah states “I am Hashem,” what does it imply?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">In which way did Hashem reveal Himself to the Avos? And in which not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which promises to the Avos were fulfilled and which were not?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How were the Avos considered better than Moshe Rabeinu?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why didn’t the people listen to Moshe’s words?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What is the purpose of mentioning the children of Reuven and Shimon?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was only Levi’s age mentioned, not the others’?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">When considering marriage, which members of the bride’s family need to be checked? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How do we know that Moshe and Aharon were equals in greatness? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Paroh visit the river each morning?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Aharon, not Moshe, bring the <glossterm>makah</glossterm> (plague) of blood?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why was <emphasis role="bold">blood</emphasis> the first makah? Where did the Egyptians get drinking water?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How long did each makah last?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which other makah was brought by Aharon? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which makos were the magicians able to duplicate?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which makah did they admit was caused by Heaven? Why?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After which makah did Paroh promise to let them leave?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">After the makah of <glossterm>arov</glossterm> (wild animals) what happened to the animals?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">For which makos does it say that there would be a separation between the Egyptians and the Jews?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe refuse to offer sacrifices inside Mitzrayim?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which miracles had to occur during the makah of <glossterm>sh’chin</glossterm> (boils)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which cattle were not hurt by the makos of <glossterm>dever</glossterm> and <glossterm>bored</glossterm> (death and hail)? Proof?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which miracle occurred during the makah of bored (hail)? What can we learn from it?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Why did Moshe insist on davening outside of the city during the makah of borod but not during the makah of <glossterm>tzefardeia</glossterm> (frogs)?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which makah equaled all the other makos in severity?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">How can we learn the <glossterm>midoh</glossterm> (trait?) of gratitude from some of the makos?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which makos are <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> described in the parsha?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which posuk is the source for the four cups of wine we drink at the Seder?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">Which month is blessed on this Shabbos? When is Rosh Chodesh?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para dir="ltr">What ‘special days’ occur during the coming month?</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>
